<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>U.S. Forest Service</origin>
<pubdate>20260206</pubdate>
<pubtime>062013</pubtime>
<title>S_USA.Activity_CFLRP_PL</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<othercit>Congress established the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program (CFLRP) with Title IV of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009. The 10-year initiative encourages the collaborative, science-based ecosystem restoration of priority landscapes on National Forests. The purpose is to conduct hazardous fuel treatments and ecosystem restoration that encourages economic and social sustainability, leverages local resources with national and private resources, reduces wildfire management costs, and addresses the utilization of forest restoration byproducts to offset treatment costs and benefit local economies. http://www.fs.fed.us/restoration/CFLRP/overview.shtml</othercit>
<onlink>http://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/datasets.php</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>CFLRP_PL represents Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration (CFLR) Program project activities in the format of a polygon vector. Also included are other High Priority Restoration projects that are funded outside of CFLR. It is important to note that this layer does not contain all of the approved project activities. Instead, these are the accomplishments that project groups uploaded to the Forest Service corporate data holdings in FACTS. As spatial data is a new requirement for the program, improvements to the quality and comprehensiveness of this data is expected in coming years. The Forest Service's Natural Resource Manager (NRM) Forest Activity Tracking System (FACTS) is the agency standard for managing information about activities related to fire/fuels, silviculture, and invasive species. FACTS is an activity tracking application for all levels of the Forest Service. The application allows tracking and monitoring of National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) decisions as well as the ability to create and manage Knutson-Vandenberg (KV) trust fund plans at the timber sale level. This application complements its companion NRM applications, which cover the spectrum of living and non-living natural resource information.</abstract>
<purpose>The Activity_CFLRP_PL represents polygon activities of projects in the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration (CFLR) Program. Also included are polygonal activities of other High Priority Restoration (HPR) projects that are funded outside of CFLR. Activities are implemented to reach the objectives outlined in a project groups' Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration proposal and are self-reported by Forest Service Units.</purpose>
<supplinf>A required set of core attributes must be collected during field work and electronically stored in the corporate NRM FACTS application to meet the minimum business needs of this protocol. Required attributes are established to meet corporate expectations of reporting, monitoring or data sharing. All required and optional fields in this protocol are supported in the NRM FACTS application. Some attributes are auto-generated and populated in the FACTS application from the spatial feature. Detailed attribute descriptions and collection standards follow later in this document under Resource, Fields, Entity and Attribute Information.</supplinf>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20160212</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>publication date</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>In work</progress>
<update>Daily</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-124.120612</westbc>
<eastbc>-81.593860</eastbc>
<northbc>49.000641</northbc>
<southbc>30.179761</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
<themekey>Activities</themekey>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>Priority Forest Landscapes</themekey>
<themekey>Ecosystem Restoration</themekey>
<themekey>U.S. Forest Service</themekey>
<themekey>Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration</themekey>
<themekey>Vegetation Management</themekey>
</theme>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<datacred>United States Forest Service Natural Resource Manager (NRM) Forest Activity Tracking System (FACTS) http://www.fs.fed.us/restoration/CFLRP/overview.shtml</datacred>
<native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.7.1.11595</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<logic>Data entry is accomplished by authorized Forest Service personnel through a web application behind the U.S. Forest Service firewall and is restricted by access requirement protocols. Further data checks occur during data migration, where certain fields such as ETL_MODIFIED and EDW_INSERT_DATE are populated with valid information.</logic>
<complete>Data is accurate up to the publication date and attribute domains are valid values from Natural Resource Manager (NRM) Forest Activity Tracking System (FACTS).</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>Generally the source information used to record spatial locations are from: 1) on-screen digitizing with a georeferenced topographic or image background; or 2) GPS field collected positions.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Data from an Oracle Activity view with Project type like CFLRP is joined to the spatial NRM FACTS Activity polygons based on SUID. Polygons are duplicated for each record coming from the Oracle view. This process is run Sunday through Friday nights.</procdesc>
<procdate>20160212</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>88616</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.Activity_CFLRP_PL</enttypl>
<enttypd>A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
<enttypds>http://support.esri.com/en/knowledgebase/GISDictionary/term/feature%20class</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACTIVITY_CODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The activity code is a 4-digit code that represents an activity. FACTS activity codes are numerically grouped into these categories: 1000 = Fire; 2000 = Range; 3000 = Cultural Resources and Recreation; 4000 = Timber and Silviculture; 5000 = Soil, Air and Watershed; 6000 = Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries; 7000 = Vegetation/Restoration; 8000 = Miscellaneous; 9000 = Engineering.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>FACTS (Forest Service Activity Tracking System) database within NRM (National Resource Manager: a suite of applications, each of which collects, stores and reports data for various Forest Service business areas).</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1101</edomv>
<edomvd>Burn Plan - Fuels: Tracks the number of burn plan documents as each. Not a fuels treatment activity code. This is a point feature type. Not valid for hazardous fuels reporting. This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1111</edomv>
<edomvd>Broadcast Burning - Covers a majority of the unit: Prescribed burning activity where fire is applied to the majority or all of an area within well- defined boundaries for reduction of fuel hazard, as a resource management treatment, or both. Beginning in FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if funded with WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels). This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1112</edomv>
<edomvd>Jackpot Burning - Scattered concentrations: Prescribed burning of fuels in scattered concentrations. Does not cover a majority of the unit. Beginning in FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if funded with WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels). This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1113</edomv>
<edomvd>Underburn - Low Intensity (Majority of Unit): Prescribed burns of low intensity covering a majority of the burn unit consuming surface fuels, but not the overstory canopy. Ladder fuels can be consumed or scorched. Includes ecosystem burning. Beginning in FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if funded with WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels). This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1117</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildfire - Natural Ignition: Enter as key point 6 if the acres burned are determined as meeting land management planning objectives in the post-assessment. These acres will count toward the unified target, and must be recorded in FACTS. May also be used with key point 0 for acres that do not meet objectives - if desired. This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1120</edomv>
<edomvd>Yarding - Removal of Fuels by Carrying or Dragging: Includes any activity that removes fuel from the site by carrying or dragging. Beginning FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels) funds are used. This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1130</edomv>
<edomvd>Burning of Piled Material: Pile Burn. Burning of piled material including hand and machine piles and decks. Beginning FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels) funds are used. This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1131</edomv>
<edomvd>Cover brush pile for burning: This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1136</edomv>
<edomvd>Pruning to Raise Canopy Height and Discourage Crown Fire: Fuels Pruning. Removal of live or dead branches from standing trees to raise the canopy base height and discourage initiation of crown fire. Beginning FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels) funds are used. This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1140</edomv>
<edomvd>Fireline Construction: Part of a control line that is scraped or dug to mineral soil. Not valid for hazardous fuels reporting. This is a line feature type activity. This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1150</edomv>
<edomvd>Rearrangement of Fuels: Any rearranging of fuels such as limbs, tops, or brush to reduce fuel bed depth or speed up decomposition. Includes slashing and lop and scatter. Beginning FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels) funds are used. This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1152</edomv>
<edomvd>Compacting/Crushing of Fuels: Any crushing, mowing, mulching or other treatment that grinds or shreds fuels, leaving resulting material on the forest floor. Beginning FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels) funds are used. This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1153</edomv>
<edomvd>Piling of Fuels, Hand or Machine: Hand or machine piling of fuels. Beginning FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels) funds are used. This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1154</edomv>
<edomvd>Chipping of Fuels: Breaking down/or slicing of trees, changing the size or shape into smaller pieces. Includes leaving on site or removing. Beginning FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature if funded with WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels). This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1160</edomv>
<edomvd>Thinning for Hazardous Fuels Reduction: Fuels Thinning. Selective felling of trees and shrubs for non-commercial hazardous fuels reduction purposes only. Beginning FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if WFHF funds are used. This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1180</edomv>
<edomvd>Fuel Break: Vegetative treatment to change fuel characteristics in such a way that expected fire behavior would be reduced. Beginning FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if funded with WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels). This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1182</edomv>
<edomvd>Post Treatment Exam Fuels Mgt.: Post Treatment Exam for Fuels Management. Not valid for hazardous fuels reporting. Beginning FY09 these accomplishments require an associated spatial polygon feature, if funded with WFHF (Wildland Fire / Hazardous Fuels). This activity code is in the Fire grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2000</edomv>
<edomvd>Range Grazing Systems: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2012</edomv>
<edomvd>Acres Improved Through Construction/Re-construction of Range Grazing Structural Improvements: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2025</edomv>
<edomvd>Range Grazing Non-Structural Improvements Maintenance: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2101</edomv>
<edomvd>Nonrange Fences - Area: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2111</edomv>
<edomvd>Range Fences - Area: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2121</edomv>
<edomvd>Range Fence Obliteration - Area: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2132</edomv>
<edomvd>Acres Improved Through Removal of Range Structural Improvements: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2310</edomv>
<edomvd>Range Fertilization: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2320</edomv>
<edomvd>Range Seeding and Planting: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2321</edomv>
<edomvd>Range Forage Improvement: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2341</edomv>
<edomvd>Range Cover Manipulation: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2360</edomv>
<edomvd>Range Control Vegetation: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2370</edomv>
<edomvd>Range Piling Slash: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2400</edomv>
<edomvd>Tree Encroachment Control: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2510</edomv>
<edomvd>Invasive - Pesticide Application: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2520</edomv>
<edomvd>Invasive - Treatment Activity Monitoring: (can only be used with CWKV funding) This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2530</edomv>
<edomvd>Invasive - Mechanical/Physical: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2540</edomv>
<edomvd>Invasive - Cultural/Fire: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2550</edomv>
<edomvd>Invasive - Biocontrol, Classic: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2560</edomv>
<edomvd>Invasive - Biocontrol, Livestock: This activity code is in the Range grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>3020</edomv>
<edomvd>Cultural Resource Monitoring: This activity code is in the Cultural Resources and Recreation grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>3045</edomv>
<edomvd>Cultural Site Protection: This activity code is in the Cultural Resources and Recreation grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>3132</edomv>
<edomvd>Cultural Resources and Recreation</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>3175</edomv>
<edomvd>Management &amp; Control of Recreation to Protect Resources: This activity code is in the Cultural Resources and Recreation grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>3370</edomv>
<edomvd>Precommercial thinning for visual: This activity code is in the Cultural Resources and Recreation grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>3400</edomv>
<edomvd>Wilderness Resources Activities: This activity code is in the Cultural Resources and Recreation grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4041</edomv>
<edomvd>Research Areas: Areas established for research purposes by experiment stations, universities or similar. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4101</edomv>
<edomvd>Coppice Cut - EA (even age) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A regeneration method in which all trees in the previous stand are cut and the majority of the regeneration is from sprouts or root suckers. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4111</edomv>
<edomvd>Patch Clearcut - EA (even age) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A type of stand clearcutting where patches (or strips) are clearcut within an individual stand boundary in two or more entries to produce an even-aged stand. As even-aged, the range of tree ages is usually less than 20 percent of the rotation after harvest of all patches. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4113</edomv>
<edomvd>Stand Clearcut - EA (even age) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): An even-aged regeneration or harvest method that removes all trees in the stand producing a fully exposed microclimate for the development of a new age class in one entry. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4115</edomv>
<edomvd>Patch Clearcut (w/ leave trees) - EA (even age) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A type of stand clearcutting where patches (or strips) are clearcut within an individual stand boundary in two or more entries to produce an even-aged stand. As even-aged, the range of tree ages is usually less than 20 percent of the rotation after harvest of all patches. A minor (less than approximately 10% of full stocking) live component may be retained for reasons other than regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4117</edomv>
<edomvd>Stand Clearcut (w/ leave trees) - EA (even age) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): An even-aged regeneration or harvest method that removes most trees in the stand producing an exposed microclimate for the development of a new age class in one entry. A minor (less than approximately 10% of full stocking) live component is retained for reasons other than regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4121</edomv>
<edomvd>Shelterwood Preparatory Cut - EA (even age) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): An optional cut to enhance conditions for seed production and/or develop windfirmness for a future shelterwood establishment cut. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4131</edomv>
<edomvd>Shelterwood Establishment Cut (with or without leave trees) - EA (even age) / RH (regeneration harvest) / NFH (not final harvest): A type of cut that removes trees except those needed for the purposes of shelter and or seed production. Prepares the seed bed and creates a new age class in a moderated microenvironment. Additional trees may be retained to provide a minor (less than approximately 10% of full stocking) live component after the removal cut for reasons other than regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4132</edomv>
<edomvd>Seed-tree Seed Cut (with and without leave trees) - EA (even age) / RH (regeneration harvest) / NFH (not final harvest): A type of cut that removes trees except those needed for the purposes of seed production. Prepares the seed bed and creates a new age class in an exposed microenvironment. Additional trees may be retained to provide a minor (less than approximately10% of full stocking) live component after the removal cut, for reasons other than regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4141</edomv>
<edomvd>Shelterwood Removal Cut - EA (even age) / NRH (not regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A final removal cut that releases established regeneration from competition with the overwood after it is no longer needed for shelter under the shelterwood regeneration method. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4142</edomv>
<edomvd>Seed-tree Final Cut - EA (even age) / NRH (not regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A final removal cut that releases established regeneration from competition with seed-trees after they are no longer needed for seed under the seed-tree regeneration method. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4143</edomv>
<edomvd>Overstory Removal Cut (from advanced regeneration) - EA (even age) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): The cutting of trees constituting an upper canopy layer to release understory trees. The primary source of regeneration is advance reproduction. A minor (less than approximately 10% of full stocking), live component of the upper canopy may be retained for reasons other than regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4145</edomv>
<edomvd>Shelterwood Removal Cut (w/ leave trees) - EA (even age) / NRH (not regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A final removal cut that releases established regeneration from competition with the overwood after it is no longer needed for shelter under the shelterwood regeneration method. A minor (less than approximately 10% of full stocking) live component may be retained for reasons other than regeneration. Historical use: (prior to 2009) 4145 was an "overstory removal cut" not associated with a shelterwood sequence although it was used inconsistently across regions. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4146</edomv>
<edomvd>Seed-tree Removal Cut (w/ leave trees) - EA (even age) / NRH (not regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A final removal cut that releases established regeneration from competition with seed-trees after they are no longer needed for seed under the seed-tree regeneration method. A minor (less than approximately 10% of full stocking) live component may be retained for reasons other than regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4151</edomv>
<edomvd>Single-tree Selection Cut - UA (uneven aged) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): An uneven-aged regeneration method where individual trees of all size classes are removed more or less uniformly throughout the stand creating or maintaining a multi-age structure to promote growth of remaining trees and to provide space for regeneration. Multiple entries of this activity ultimately results in an uneven- aged stand of 3 or more age classes. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4152</edomv>
<edomvd>Group Selection Cut - UA (uneven aged) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): An uneven-aged regeneration method in which trees are cut in small groups and new age classes are established. The width of groups is commonly less than approximately twice the height of the mature trees. Individual trees in the matrix may or may not be harvested to provide improved growing conditions for remaining trees. Multiple entries of this activity ultimately results in an uneven-aged stand of 3 or more age classes. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4162</edomv>
<edomvd>Two-aged Coppice Cut (with residual trees) - 2A (2 ages) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A two-aged regeneration method in which the majority of the regeneration is from sprouts or root suckers. Sufficient residual trees, representing at least approximately 10% of full stocking, are retained to attain goals other than regeneration and create a two-aged stand. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4177</edomv>
<edomvd>Two-aged Stand Clearcut (with residual trees) - 2A (2 ages) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A two-aged regeneration or harvest method that removes sufficient trees to produce an exposed microclimate for the development of a new age class. Sufficient residual trees, representing at least approximately 10% of full stocking, are retained to attain goals other than regeneration and create a two-aged stand. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4183</edomv>
<edomvd>Two-aged Seed-tree Seed and Removal Cut (with residual trees) - 2A (2 ages) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A final removal cut that removes trees except those needed for regeneration and sufficient reserve trees, representing at least approximately 10% of full stocking, to attain goals other than regeneration and create a two- aged stand. It also produces an exposed microclimate for the development of a new age class. This is both the seed cut and the final harvest since the seed-trees and the reserves will be retained to create a two-aged stand. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4193</edomv>
<edomvd>Two-aged Shelterwood Establishment and Removal Cut (with residual trees) - 2A (2 ages) / RH (regeneration harvest) / FH (final harvest): A type of cut that removes trees except those needed for regeneration and sufficient residual trees representing at least approximately 10% of full stocking. Prepares the seed bed and creates a new age class in a moderated microenvironment. This is both the establishment and the final removal harvest since the overwood trees and the reserves will be retained to create a two- aged stand. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4194</edomv>
<edomvd>Two-aged Shelterwood Establishment Cut (with residual trees) - 2A (2 ages) / RH (regeneration harvest) / NFH (non final harvest): A type of establishment cut that removes trees except those needed for regeneration and sufficient residual trees representing at least approximately 10% of full stocking. Prepares the seed bed and creates a new age class in a moderated microenvironment. This establishment cut will be followed by the final harvest which will leave at least approximately 10% full stocking to create a two-aged stand. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4210</edomv>
<edomvd>Improvement Cut: An intermediate harvest which removes the less desirable trees of any species in a stand of poles or larger trees, primarily to improve the composition and quality. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4211</edomv>
<edomvd>Liberation Cut: An intermediate harvest intended as a release treatment in a stand not past the sapling stage to free the favored trees from competition with older, overtopping trees. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4220</edomv>
<edomvd>Commercial Thin: An intermediate harvest with the objective of reducing stand density primarily to improve growth, enhance forest health, and other resources objectives. Treatment can recover potential mortality while producing merchantable material. Thinning includes the following: chemical (killing of unwanted trees by herbicide application); crown (removal of trees from dominant and co-dominant strata); free (no consideration to crown position); low (removal of trees from lower crown classes); mechanical or row (removal of trees either in row, strips by using a fixed spacing interval); selection (removal of the crown class to favor those in the lower crown classes.) This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4231</edomv>
<edomvd>Salvage Cut (intermediate treatment, not regeneration): An intermediate harvest removing trees which are dead or dying because of injurious agents other than competition, to recover economic value that would otherwise be lost. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4232</edomv>
<edomvd>Sanitation Cut: An intermediate harvest removing trees to improve stand health by stopping or reducing the actual or anticipated spread of insects and disease. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4241</edomv>
<edomvd>Special Products Removal: Harvest and removal of Special Forest Products as described in FSH 2409.18 87.05-Definitions, where the removal cannot be described as a silvicultural treatment. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4242</edomv>
<edomvd>Harvest Without Restocking: The harvesting of trees from lands where the restocking of trees is not desired to meet desired vegetative conditions (reference FSH 1909.12, 64.2.). This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4250</edomv>
<edomvd>Natural Changes (excludes fire): Substantial alterations to the structure, composition, or density of the forest vegetation. This includes changes due to natural occurrences such as wind, ice, landslide, insect epidemic, beaver impoundment, etc. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4270</edomv>
<edomvd>Permanent Land Clearing: A permanent change in site conditions that would prevent continued site occupancy of forest vegetation. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4310</edomv>
<edomvd>Silvicultural Stand Examination: Collection of stand, plot, tree and vegetation information to predetermined standards and recording of such information in such a manner that it can be retrieved and used at a later time for a variety of reasons. Includes polygon delineation, data management, evaluation and field data collection. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4314</edomv>
<edomvd>Pretreatment Exam for Reforestation: Collection of field data to determine the amount and type of treatment (site preparation, planting, etc.) needed to meet management objectives in areas of unknown stocking. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4315</edomv>
<edomvd>Pretreatment Exam for Release or Precommercial Thinning: Collection of field data to determine the amount and type of stand improvement needed. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4319</edomv>
<edomvd>Low Intensity Stand Examination: Collection of stand information to a standard such as would be attained by a walk through examination. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4320</edomv>
<edomvd>Stand Diagnosis Prepared: The preparation of a stand diagnosis which is the process used to determine stand treatment needs, such as timber removal, prescribed fire, thinning, or regeneration based on existing or anticipated site conditions and management direction. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4331</edomv>
<edomvd>Stand Silviculture Prescription: A document written or approved by a certified silviculturist that describes management activities needed to implement a silvicultural treatment or treatment sequence at the stand level. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4332</edomv>
<edomvd>Interdisciplinary Compartment Prescription: The creation of a compartment prescription integrating the objectives from the forest plan. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4341</edomv>
<edomvd>Stocking Survey: Collection of information on planted, seeded and/or natural regeneration to monitor stocking, seedling health and potential future treatment needs. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4342</edomv>
<edomvd>Plantation Survival Survey: Collection of information from staked trees to determine survival of species and seed lots on a site and as a representation of all species and sites for a given year This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4343</edomv>
<edomvd>Animal Damage Survey: Collection of field data to determine if animal control to protect forest regeneration is needed and/or if the animal control previously applied to protect seedlings was effective. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4344</edomv>
<edomvd>Vegetative Competition Survey: Collection of information to determine if vegetation control is needed to protect the forest regeneration and/or if the vegetation control was successful. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4346</edomv>
<edomvd>Post Treatment Vegetation Monitoring: The collection of information to evaluate the completeness and effectiveness of a vegetation treatment. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4381</edomv>
<edomvd>Certification of Natural Regeneration with Site Prep: Certification that natural reproduction has attained stocking levels at or above the minimum defined levels in terms of number and distribution of acceptable species on a site where prior site preparation had been done. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4382</edomv>
<edomvd>Certification of Natural Regeneration without Site Prep: Certification that natural reproduction has attained stocking levels at or above the minimum defined levels in terms of number and distribution of acceptable species on a site where prior site preparation had not been done. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4383</edomv>
<edomvd>Certification-Planted: Certification that the planted area has achieved stocking levels at or above the minimum defined levels in terms of number and distribution of acceptable species. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4391</edomv>
<edomvd>TSI Certification - Release/weeding: This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4392</edomv>
<edomvd>TSI Certification - Thinning: This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4401</edomv>
<edomvd>Reforestation Need Created by Harvest: This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4402</edomv>
<edomvd>Reforestation Need Created by Fire: This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4431</edomv>
<edomvd>Plant Trees: The establishment or re-establishment of forest cover artificially by planting seedlings and/or cuttings with or without site preparation. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4432</edomv>
<edomvd>Fill-in or Replant Trees: The reestablishment of forest cover artificially by planting seedlings and/or cuttings, with or without site preparation where the site was previously treated and treatment was not completely successful and or subsequently failed. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4448</edomv>
<edomvd>Plant or Seed Shrubs, Forbs, Grasses: The establishment of shrubs, forbs, and/or grasses artificially by planting seedlings, plugs, roots and/or cuttings, and or sowing seeds This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4450</edomv>
<edomvd>Reforestation Enhancement: The installation of an enhancement that would protect or enhance the growth and survival of the establishing tree seedlings. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4451</edomv>
<edomvd>Reforestation Enhancement Maintenance: The maintenance of an enhancement that would protect or enhance the growth and survival of the establishing tree seedlings. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4452</edomv>
<edomvd>Initiate Natural Regeneration: The use of natural regeneration to establish a new age class from natural seeding, sprouting or suckering. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4453</edomv>
<edomvd>Natural Recovery: The use of natural processes to revegetate an area after a disturbance (such as fire) and the acceptance of resulting conditions, even though it may take many years to attain stocked forested conditions. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4455</edomv>
<edomvd>Slashing - Pre-Site Preparation: An activity done to a site in advance of site preparation designed to enhance the success of the site preparation treatment. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4460</edomv>
<edomvd>Animal Damage Control for Reforestation: The use of fencing, tubing, bud caps, seed caps, repellents or trapping, killing or otherwise controlling animals so as to protect or enhance the growth and survival of the newly establishing forest regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4461</edomv>
<edomvd>Maintenance of Animal Damage Control for Reforestation: The maintenance of fencing, tubing, bud caps, seed caps, repellents or traps, for the control of animals so as to protect or enhance the growth and survival of the newly establishing forest regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4466</edomv>
<edomvd>Leave Tree Protection: Protection of residual trees to reduce damage from subsequent activities such as hazard reduction. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4471</edomv>
<edomvd>Site Preparation for Planting - Burning: Manipulation of a site by prescribed burning to enhance the success of regeneration on sites that will be planted. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4472</edomv>
<edomvd>Site Preparation for Planting - Chemical: Manipulation of a site using chemical methods to enhance the success of regeneration on sites that will be planted. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4473</edomv>
<edomvd>Site Preparation for Planting - Other: Manipulation of a site, by methods other than burning, chemical, mechanical, or manual. to enhance the success of regeneration on sites that will be planted. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4474</edomv>
<edomvd>Site Preparation for Planting - Mechanical: Mechanical manipulation of a site to enhance the success of regeneration on sites that will be planted. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4475</edomv>
<edomvd>Site Preparation for Planting - Manual: Manipulation of a site using manual methods to enhance the success of regeneration on sites that will be planted. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4491</edomv>
<edomvd>Site Preparation for Seeding - Manual: Manipulation of a site using manual methods to enhance the success of regeneration on sites that will be seeded. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4492</edomv>
<edomvd>Site Preparation for Natural Regeneration - Chemical: Manipulation of a site using chemical methods to enhance the success of natural regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4493</edomv>
<edomvd>Site Preparation for Natural Regeneration - Other: Manipulation of a site by methods other than burning, chemical, mechanical or manual, to enhance the success of natural regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4494</edomv>
<edomvd>Site Preparation for Natural Regeneration - Mechanical: Manipulation of a site using mechanical methods to enhance the success of natural regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4495</edomv>
<edomvd>Site Preparation for Natural Regeneration - Manual: Manipulation of a site using manual methods to enhance the success of natural regeneration. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4511</edomv>
<edomvd>Tree Release and Weed: A treatment designed to free young trees from undesirable, competing vegetation. Includes cleaning and weeding which are done in stands not past sapling stage. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4521</edomv>
<edomvd>Precommercial Thin: The selective felling, deadening, or removal of trees from a young stand maintaining a specific stocking or stand density range. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4530</edomv>
<edomvd>Prune: The removal, close to the branch collar or flush with stem, of side branches (live or dead) and multiple leaders from a standing live tree. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4540</edomv>
<edomvd>Control of Understory Vegetation: Removal or killing of vegetation under the overstory of trees by any method except burning. (e.g., Hand, chemical, ,or mechanized) This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4541</edomv>
<edomvd>Control of Understory Vegetation- Burning: Removal or killing of vegetation under the overstory of trees by burning. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4560</edomv>
<edomvd>Animal Control for TSI: The use of fencing, tubing, bud caps, seed caps, repellents or trapping, killing or otherwise controlling animals so as to protect or enhance the growth of established forest vegetation not past the sapling stage. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4631</edomv>
<edomvd>Layout and Design: Part of Gate 3, Sale Preparation. Layout and design of timber harvest units. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4632</edomv>
<edomvd>Marking/Designation: Part of Gate 3, Sale Preparation. Timber marking and designation of timber for removal. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4633</edomv>
<edomvd>Cruising: Part of Gate 3, Sale Preparation. Volume determination This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4810</edomv>
<edomvd>Cone Collection: Collection of cones, seed, or fruit structures for operational reforestation from wild stands. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4910</edomv>
<edomvd>Selection and Care of Superior Trees: Searching for and designating phenotypically superior trees from a larger population and maintaining labels, records and health of these trees. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4933</edomv>
<edomvd>Seed Production Area Cone Collection: This activity describes collection and handling of cones or fruits collected from seed production areas. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4941</edomv>
<edomvd>Seed Orchard Operations: Seed orchard maintenance includes thinning to improve spacing or remove undesirable individuals, rouging to remove genetically inferior individuals or families, fertilization, floral stimulation, pruning, graft maintenance, application of pesticides, rodent control, mowing, fence maintenance, fire break maintenance, label maintenance and records maintenance. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>4951</edomv>
<edomvd>Genetic Evaluation Plantation Operations: Maintenance of evaluation plantations including control of competing vegetation, maintaining labels and records, maintaining fences, and in some cases thinning. This activity code is in the Timber and Silviculture grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>5100</edomv>
<edomvd>Watershed Resource Activities: This activity code is in the Soil, Air and Watershed grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>5230</edomv>
<edomvd>Watershed Analysis: This activity code is in the Soil, Air and Watershed grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>5510</edomv>
<edomvd>Watershed Resource Non- Structural Improvements Erosion Cont: This activity code is in the Soil, Air and Watershed grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>5520</edomv>
<edomvd>Watershed Resource Non- Structural Improvements Riparian: This activity code is in the Soil, Air and Watershed grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>5530</edomv>
<edomvd>Watershed Resource Non- Structural Improvements Stream Channel: This activity code is in the Soil, Air and Watershed grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>5540</edomv>
<edomvd>Watershed Resource Non- Structural Improvements Maintenance: This activity code is in the Soil, Air and Watershed grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>5550</edomv>
<edomvd>Watershed Resource Non- Structural Improvements Soil Productivity: This activity code is in the Soil, Air and Watershed grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>5630</edomv>
<edomvd>Watershed Resource Road Closure - Length: This activity code is in the Soil, Air and Watershed grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>5633</edomv>
<edomvd>Scarify and Seed Landings: This activity code is in the Soil, Air and Watershed grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6000</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Activities: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6010</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife habitat inventory: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6030</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife habitat monitoring - area: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6050</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Improvement: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6080</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Seeding and planting: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6100</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Non-Structural Improvement: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6101</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Prescribed fire: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6102</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Release and weeding: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6103</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Precommercial thinning: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6104</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Regeneration cut: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6105</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Intermediate cut: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6106</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Chemical treatment: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6107</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Mechanical treatment: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6111</edomv>
<edomvd>Leave Trees (Wildlife Reasons) - Area: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6120</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Access management (Closure Area): This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6130</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Create openings: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6131</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Rehabilitate openings: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6133</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildlife Habitat Slash treatment: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6400</edomv>
<edomvd>TES and Sensitive Species Activities: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6421</edomv>
<edomvd>Sensitive Species survey: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6424</edomv>
<edomvd>TES Recovery Plan: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6430</edomv>
<edomvd>T&amp;ES resource monitoring: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6450</edomv>
<edomvd>T&amp;ES non-structural improvement: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6600</edomv>
<edomvd>Inland Fisheries Habitat Improvement Activities: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6610</edomv>
<edomvd>Inland Fish habitat inventory: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6620</edomv>
<edomvd>Inland fish habitat monitoring: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6674</edomv>
<edomvd>Inland Fish habitat fertilization - Area: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>6684</edomv>
<edomvd>Inland Fish Thinning for Fish Habitat Improvement: This activity code is in the Wildlife; Threatened, Endangered, and Sensitive, and Fisheries grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>7030</edomv>
<edomvd>Seeding grasses, forbs and/or shrubs: The establishment of shrubs, forbs, and/or grasses by actively sowing seeds. This activity code is in the Vegetation/Restoration grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>7031</edomv>
<edomvd>Planting propagules and cuttings: The establishment of shrubs, forbs, and/or grasses by actively planting plugs, roots, cuttings and other plant materials. This activity code is in the Vegetation/Restoration grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>7065</edomv>
<edomvd>Re-vegetation treatments - vegetation removal: A treatment designed to favor target revegetation by removing undesirable, competing vegetation. This could include clearing, grubbing, weeding, mowing and other similar activities. This activity code is in the Vegetation/Restoration grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>7067</edomv>
<edomvd>Re-vegetation treatments - herbicides: A treatment designed to favor target revegetation by removing undesirable, competing vegetation through the use of herbicides. This activity code is in the Vegetation/Restoration grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>7075</edomv>
<edomvd>Wildland seed collecting: Collection of seeds and fruit from native plant communities for revegetation purposes. The intent is that materials collected are genetically original to the collection site and come from endemic or indigenous taxa. This activity code is in the Vegetation/Restoration grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>7100</edomv>
<edomvd>Pollinator habitat improved, restored or maintained: This activity code is in the Vegetation/Restoration grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>8120</edomv>
<edomvd>Disease Prevention: This activity code is in the Miscellaneous grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>8200</edomv>
<edomvd>Insect Control: This activity code is in the Miscellaneous grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>8220</edomv>
<edomvd>Insect Prevention: This activity code is in the Miscellaneous grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>9008</edomv>
<edomvd>Road Maintenance Vegetation Reduction: Any crushing, mowing, or other treatment that grinds or shreds roadside vegetation. Use this code to report road maintenance activities that meet the criteria for hazardous fuels reduction as defined in the current fiscal year program direction. This activity code is in the Engineering grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>9220</edomv>
<edomvd>Native Species Established: This activity code is in the Engineering grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>9300</edomv>
<edomvd>Public Information on Resource Management: This activity code is in the Engineering grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>9400</edomv>
<edomvd>Right of Way Maintenance: This activity code is in the Engineering grouping.</edomvd>
<edomvds>FACTS User Guide, Appendix B: Activity Codes</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACTIVITY_NAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>A basic description of the activity that occurred on the landscape.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Open ended textual field describing the activity that occurred.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>TREATMENT_TYPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The National Fire Plan Operations and Reporting System (NFPORS) Type Name. Defined in the NFPORS documentation as; "The minor categorization for a Treatment or Activity. The Type provides, in greater detail than the Category, a description of the work that is being done." NFPORS Types are determined by the Category.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NFPORS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The NFPORS Type Name. For example: Biomass Removal, Broadcast Burn, Chipping, Crushing, Fire Use, Grazing, Jackpot Burn, Lop and Scatter Machine Pile, Machine Pile Burn, Mastication/Mowing, or Thinning.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FUND_CODES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The expanded budget line item (EBLI) that is used to finance work.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USFS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Fund Code planned or actually used for the activity. This field can have comma separated values.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NBR_UNITS_PLANNED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The number of units planned to be done by an activity (acres, miles, point).</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The number of units planned to be done by an activity (acres, miles, point).</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NBR_UNITS_ACCOMPLISHED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The number of units of work accomplished by an activity (acres, miles, etc.).</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The number of units of work accomplished by an activity (acres, miles, etc.).</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>UOM</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The units that the data is recorded such as acres, miles, each, etc.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>ACRES</edomv>
<edomvd>Area</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>EACH</edomv>
<edomvd>Point</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MILES</edomv>
<edomvd>Distance</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DATE_PLANNED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The date that work is planned to be accomplished.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Date field</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DATE_ACCOMPLISHED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>For service contracts the date accomplished is the date of contract award. For Force Account (work done by Forest Service crews and equipment) the date accomplished is the date the work is completed.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Date field</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DATE_COMPLETED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The date that work is physically completed.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Date field</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FY_PLANNED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The Fiscal Year activity is planned. The Federal Fiscal Year begins on October 1 and ends on September 30 of the succeeding calendar year.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Fiscal Year in the form YYYY.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FY_ACCOMPLISHED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The Fiscal Year activity is accomplished. The Federal Fiscal Year begins on October 1 and ends on September 30 of the succeeding calendar year.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Fiscal Year in the form YYYY.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FY_COMPLETED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The Fiscal Year activity is completed. The Federal Fiscal Year begins on October 1 and ends on September 30 of the succeeding calendar year.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Fiscal Year in the form YYYY.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACTIVITY_UNIT_ORG</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The Activity Unit Organization is the unit in which the activity is located. It is defined by a two digit Region Code, followed by a two digit Administrative Forest Code and a two digit District Code.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>A textual field containing a code created by combining a two digit Region Code, a Two Digit Administrative Forest code and a Two Digit District Code.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>REGION_CODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>U.S. Forest Service Region, consisting of Region 01 (Northern Region), Region 02 (Rocky Mountain Region), Region 03 (Southwestern Region), Region 04 (Intermountain Region), Region 05 (Pacific Southwest Region), Region 06 (Pacific Northwest Region), Region 08 (Southern Region), Region 09 (Eastern Region), and Region 10 (Alaska Region). There is no Region 07. Regions are listed on http://www.fs.fed.us/organization/506.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Region numbers as text.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ADMIN_FOREST_CODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The numerical code of the US Forest that administers the land.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The numerical code of the US Forest that administers the land. Forests are subdivisions of regions and can be found by drilling through regions on http://www.fs.fed.us/organization/506.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DISTRICT_CODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The USFS Ranger District where the project is located. This code uniquely identifies a Ranger District within a forest. For example, 01-17-01 is the Salmon River Ranger District in the Nez Perce-Clearwater National Forests in Region 01.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Ranger District Codes.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>HOME_ORG</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The Home Organization is the unit in which the activity is located. It is defined by a two digit Region Code, followed by a two digit Administrative Forest Code and a two digit District Code.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>A textual field containing a code created by combining a two digit Region Code, a Two Digit Administrative Forest code and a Two Digit District Code. Codes can be found on http://www.fs.fed.us/organization/506.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ADMIN_FOREST_NAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the U.S. Forest that administers the land. Forests are subdivisions of regions and can be found by drilling through regions on http://www.fs.fed.us/organization/506.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Forest names.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ADMIN_DISTRICT_NAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the Ranger District where the project is located. Ranger districts are subdivisions of U.S. Forests.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Ranger District Names.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PROCLAIMED_FOREST_CODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The Forest within which the activity unit is physically located on the ground. This may or may not be the same Forest name and number that is administering that piece of ground or performing the activity (the Administrative Forest).</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>A textual field containing a code created by combining a two digit Region Code, a Two Digit Administrative Forest code and a Two Digit District Code. Codes can be found on http://www.fs.fed.us/organization/506.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OWNERSHIP_CODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The entity (person, Agency, Tribe, or company) that owns the land where the activity unit is located.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>ARL</edomv>
<edomvd>Agriculture Research Land</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>BIA</edomv>
<edomvd>Bureau of Indian Affairs</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>BOR</edomv>
<edomvd>City/Borough Lands</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>BLM</edomv>
<edomvd>Bureau of Land Management</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>BRC</edomv>
<edomvd>Bureau of Reclamation</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>COE</edomv>
<edomvd>Corps of Engineers</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>CTL</edomv>
<edomvd>Conservation Trust</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>CTY</edomv>
<edomvd>County</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>DOD</edomv>
<edomvd>Department of Defense</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>DOE</edomv>
<edomvd>Department of Energy</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>ESL</edomv>
<edomvd>Encumbered Selected Lands</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>FFP</edomv>
<edomvd>Foreign Forestry</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>FOA</edomv>
<edomvd>Foreign Other Agency</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>FPV</edomv>
<edomvd>Foreign Private</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>FS</edomv>
<edomvd>USDA Forest Service</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>FWS</edomv>
<edomvd>US Fish and Wildlife Service</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>IND</edomv>
<edomvd>Indian Lands</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MIN</edomv>
<edomvd>Mining Claims</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MUN</edomv>
<edomvd>Municipal Owned/Mgmt</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>NPS</edomv>
<edomvd>National Park Service</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>NWR</edomv>
<edomvd>National Wildlife Refuge</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>O&amp;C</edomv>
<edomvd>O&amp;C Lands</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>OFA</edomv>
<edomvd>Other Federal Agencies</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>OGV</edomv>
<edomvd>Other Government Agencies</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>OLA</edomv>
<edomvd>Other Local Agencies</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>OSA</edomv>
<edomvd>Other State Agencies</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PIF</edomv>
<edomvd>Industrial Forestry</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PIO</edomv>
<edomvd>Industrial Other</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PUB</edomv>
<edomvd>Public (Private Citizen)</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PVT</edomv>
<edomvd>Private</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>RR</edomv>
<edomvd>Railroad</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>RUR</edomv>
<edomvd>Rural Fire Protection</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>STA</edomv>
<edomvd>State</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>STF</edomv>
<edomvd>State Forestry</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>STP</edomv>
<edomvd>State Park</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>STS</edomv>
<edomvd>State School</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>STW</edomv>
<edomvd>State Wildlife</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>TNL</edomv>
<edomvd>Tribal Nation</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OWNERSHIP_DESC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Description of the entity that owns the land where the activity unit is located.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual description of ownership.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STATE_ABBR</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Two-letter abbreviation for the primary legal subdivision of the United States.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Census Bureau</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<codesetd>
<codesetn>List of U.S. State Abbreviations</codesetn>
<codesets>http://www.census.gov/geo/reference/ansi_statetables.html</codesets>
</codesetd>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>WATERSHED_CODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The watersheds referenced in FACTS are from the nationally consistent watershed dataset that is subdivided into 6 levels (12-digit Hydrologic Unit Codes (HUC)) and is available from the USGS and USDA NRCS. The Watershed Boundary Dataset (WBD) contains the most current, the highest resolution and the most detailed delineation of the watershed boundaries.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM NRIS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<codesetd>
<codesetn>Hydrologic Unit Code (HUC).</codesetn>
<codesets>http://water.usgs.gov/GIS/huc.html</codesets>
</codesetd>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SLOPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The general incline of the land measured in vertical feet/100 horizontal feet.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Percentage</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ELEVATION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The average elevation of the activity unit in feet above sea level. The value for this field is the mid-slope elevation of the activity unit</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Feet</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ASPECT</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The cardinal direction that the landscape predominantly faces at a defined position, such as the center point of the occurrence.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Aspect - direction of slope in compass points.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>METHOD_CODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The method code represents the method planned and/or used to accomplish the activity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The method code represents the method planned and/or used to accomplish the activity.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>METHOD_DESC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The text description for the pertinent Method Code as defined in FACTS.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual description.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EQUIPMENT_CODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The numeric code for the equipment planned to or used to accomplish the activity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>3-digit code</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EQUIPMENT_DESC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Description of the Equipment Code as defined in FACTS.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual description.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>COST_PER_UOM</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Cost per Unit of Measure, such as the cost per acre. This field will accumulate costs and be over-written by costs entered in the Work Agent block. (999999.99)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The cost to do an activity per unit of measure (acres, miles or each).</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NEPA_PROJECT_ID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The NEPA Project ID field is used to uniquely identify a NEPA Project. This value is generated at the Forest level thru the Planning, Appeals, and Litigation System (PALS) and must be unique to the Forest.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) Project ID field is used to uniquely identify a NEPA Project. A value of "Not Required" may be used when the activity is not in PALS, or is a plan or survey activity.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NEPA_DOC_NAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) Document Name - The name of the project covered by the NEPA document, usually in the title of the document.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>NEPA Document Name - The name of the project covered by the NEPA document, usually in the title of the document. A value of "DEFAULT FOR NOT REQUIRED" may be used when the activity is not in PALS, or is a plan or survey activity.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>IMPLEMENTATION_PROJECT_NAMES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the implementation project. Implementation Projects are groupings of activities, such as those from a stewardship contract where many activities will take place.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The name of the implementation project.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>IMPLEMENTATION_PROJECT_NUMBERS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The number of the implementation project.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The number of the implementation project.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>IMPLEMENTATION_PROJECT_TYPES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>An identifying type for an implementation project. An implementation project type may be the abbreviation of a special program or initiative.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Examples include CFLRP (Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration), WBBS (Western Bark Beetle Strategy), and ARRA (American Recovery and Reinvestment Act). punctuation variations are present with quotes and commas.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>WORK_AGENT_CODES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The workforce code represents the responsible party that is doing the activity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PB</edomv>
<edomvd>Public - work completed by the public (other than official volunteers).</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>OT</edomv>
<edomvd>Other - work completed by another person/group (i.e., inmate crew).</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>CA</edomv>
<edomvd>Cooperative Agreement - work done under a Coop Agreement.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>HR</edomv>
<edomvd>Human Resource - work completed by human resource crews.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>OP</edomv>
<edomvd>Operator - work completed by an operator or their crew.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>GR</edomv>
<edomvd>Grantee - work completed by Grantee</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PR</edomv>
<edomvd>Purchaser - work completed by a purchaser or their crew.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>VL</edomv>
<edomvd>Volunteer - work completed by volunteer or volunteers.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>NA</edomv>
<edomvd>Not Applicable</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>GS</edomv>
<edomvd>Stewardship Contract - work done by Goods for Services.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>SV</edomv>
<edomvd>Stewardship Contract - work done under a Service Contract</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>FA</edomv>
<edomvd>Force Account - work completed by Forest Service crews.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>CT</edomv>
<edomvd>Contract - work completed by a contract awarded by the Forest Service.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>SC</edomv>
<edomvd>Stewardship Contract - work done under a Stewardship Contract.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>MD</edomv>
<edomvd>Stewardship Contract - work done under a Timber Sale Contract Modification.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>PE</edomv>
<edomvd>Permittee - work completed by Permittee.</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SUBUNIT_SIZE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Size of the subunit on which the activity occurred</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>A numerical field representing the size of the activity.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SUBUNIT_UOM</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The units that the data is recorded such as acres, miles, gallons, etc. for the subunit</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>A textual field containing the units of measurement for the activity. Often MILES.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GIS_ACRES</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACTIVITY_UNIT_CN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>An automatically generated control number for the activity unit.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>An automatically generated control number for the activity unit.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SUBUNIT_CN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>An automatically generated control number for the subunit.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>An automatically generated number representing the activity's control number.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FACTS_ID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Identifier for an activity unit (geographical area) on which activities occur. Must be 10 alpha numeric characters with no spaces.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Identifier for an activity unit (geographical area) on which activities occur. Must be 10 alpha numeric characters with no spaces.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SUID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Subunit ID. Concatenation of the Region, Forest, District, FACTS ID, and Subunit codes. The SUID identifies down to the subunit where an activity will occur within an Activity Unit. Activity Subunits can have multiple activities on them and overlap with other Subunits within the Activity Unit. SUID is alpha/numeric. SUID is one of the links between spatial and tabular data records.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The activity subunit that corresponds to the land encompassing the whole of the activity unit must have a subunit ID of '000'. When activities are performed on only a portion of an activity unit, a new subunit can be created to represent that portion. These subunits may be numbered in sequential order or you may wish to use letters that more easily identify the subunit. The subunit is identified in total by a concatenation of the AU (Activity Unit) Region, AU Proclaimed or Administrative Forest, AU District, FACTS ID, and Subunit fields. An example of a SUID is 0111021A51466541016. This first six numbers of this 19-digit code include the region/forest/district code (011102), followed by the ten-digit FACTS ID (1A51466541), and concluded with the three digit subunit (016).</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SUBUNIT</attrlabl>
<attrdef>An activity subunit is a portion of an activity unit. The activity subunit that corresponds to the land encompassing the whole of the activity unit must have a subunit ID of '000'. When activities are performed on only a portion of an activity unit, a new subunit can be created to represent that portion. These subunits may be numbered in sequential order or use letters that more easily identify the subunit.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>An activity subunit is a portion of an activity unit.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SUBUNIT_NAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Name of the subunit on which the activity occurred.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>A textual field containing a description of the subunit on which the activity occurred</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACTIVITY_CN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>An automatically generated control number for the activity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>An automatically generated control number for the activity.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>NEPA_PROJECT_CN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>A control number for the NEPA Project.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>A control number for the NEPA Project.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STAGE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Stages, as defined in FACTS, are used to spatially track an activity unit at certain points in the life of the unit. The NEPA Stage would track the activity unit at the time of the NEPA decision (if identified). The Layout Stage would track the activity unit at the time when the unit is laid out on the ground and could be the same or different than the activity unit at the NEPA Stage. The Accomplished Stage would track the activity unit when the activity that establishes the activity unit is completed. Again this could be the same or different than the NEPA and/or the Layout Stages.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2</edomv>
<edomvd>Layout</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>3</edomv>
<edomvd>Accomplished</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1</edomv>
<edomvd>NEPA</edomvd>
<edomvds>NRM FACTS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STAGE_DESC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Description of the stages.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual explanation of the Stage Code.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>REV_DATE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Date of feature creation or latest update.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Date field.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DATA_SOURCE_CODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Globally unique feature-level metadata identifier used across most Forest Service National Application databases.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>44</edomv>
<edomvd>Digital Base Map</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>08</edomv>
<edomvd>Digitized from Hardcopy Orthophoto</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>20</edomv>
<edomvd>Digitized Other</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>22</edomv>
<edomvd>Other Cadastral Information</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>30</edomv>
<edomvd>Remote Sensing Data - Base Level</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>46</edomv>
<edomvd>Digital Broad Scale Map</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>07</edomv>
<edomvd>Digitized from Hardcopy PSB/SEQ (1:24,000)</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>09</edomv>
<edomvd>Automated Lands Project (ALP)</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>24</edomv>
<edomvd>Other</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>21</edomv>
<edomvd>Geographic Coordinate Database (GCDB)</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>33</edomv>
<edomvd>Remote Sensing Data - National Level</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>31</edomv>
<edomvd>Remote Sensing Data - Mid Level</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>02</edomv>
<edomvd>GPS - Uncorrected Data</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>01</edomv>
<edomvd>Original Cartographic Feature File (CFF)</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>05</edomv>
<edomvd>Resurvey Plat</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>23</edomv>
<edomvd>Other Agency Digital</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>41</edomv>
<edomvd>Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>32</edomv>
<edomvd>Remote Sensing Data - Broad Level</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>47</edomv>
<edomvd>Other Land Survey Data</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>03</edomv>
<edomvd>GPS - Differentially Corrected Data</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>06</edomv>
<edomvd>Photogrammetric Compilation</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>04</edomv>
<edomvd>GPS Survey Grade and Sub-meter</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DATA_SOURCE_DESC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The text description for the Data Source.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The text description for the Data Source.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>CRC_VALUE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internally generated attribute for publishing.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Internally generated attribute for publishing.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>UK</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internally generated attribute for publishing.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Internally generated attribute for publishing.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EDW_INSERT_DATE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internally generated attribute for publishing.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Internally generated attribute for publishing.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACCURACY</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Distance (+/-), in dataset distance units, of expected difference between feature and real world object locations.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>NRM FACTS</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Distance (+/-), in dataset distance units, of expected difference between feature and real world object locations.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ETL_MODIFIED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internally generated attribute for publishing.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Internally generated attribute for publishing.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
</attr>
</detailed>
<overview>
<eaover>NRM FACTS application constrains some attribute values by domains and subtypes, and allows others that are free text. The completeness of the data reflects the content of the USFS NRM database at the time of extraction from the transactional database to the published Enterprise Data Warehouse (EDW) version.</eaover>
<eadetcit>U.S. Forest Service</eadetcit>
</overview>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
<distliab>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</distliab>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20230623</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
