<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Automated Lands Program (ALP)</origin>
<origin>U.S. Forest Service</origin>
<pubdate>20260208</pubdate>
<pubtime>015902</pubtime>
<title>S_USA.BdyDesg_LSRS_Wilderness</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<othercit>ArcGIS REST Services Directory: https://apps.fs.usda.gov/arcx/rest/services/EDW/EDW_Wilderness_01/MapServer</othercit>
<onlink>http://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/datasets.php</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>This dataset is intended for read-only use. These data show the current boundaries of National Wilderness areas, including all additions/deletions/modifications to boundaries which occurred after the area was originally designated. The boundaries in this dataset are suitable for general mapping and analysis. In comparison to the Wilderness dataset, the WildernessStatus dataset includes discrete polygons for all additions/deletions/modifications to boundaries which occurred after the area was originally designated, as well as action dates and other details. The purpose of these data is to provide display, identification, and analysis tools for determining current boundary information for Forest Service managers, GIS specialists, and others.</abstract>
<purpose>This dataset represents the current boundaries of areas that have been designated as a National Wilderness area in the National Wilderness Preservation System.</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20151227</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>Publication Date</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>Weekly</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-139.636233</westbc>
<eastbc>-65.770376</eastbc>
<northbc>59.999703</northbc>
<southbc>18.249764</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
<themekey>boundaries</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>Wilderness Name</themekey>
<themekey>ALP Land Dataset</themekey>
<themekey>USDA Forest Service</themekey>
<themekey>NFS Lands</themekey>
<themekey>Wilderness</themekey>
<themekey>Land Status</themekey>
</theme>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<native>Esri ArcGIS 13.3.4.52636</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<attracc>
<attraccr>The Regional Land Status personnel are responsible for their local data stewardship and maintenance. The overall collection nationwide consists of 100% attribute accuracy based on currentness and completeness.</attraccr>
</attracc>
<logic>Quality control measures taken: this feature class is populated by an automated translation process from the source feature class that is edited and maintained by the data stewards. Only stewards with the proper role grants can edit the data. The application used for editing has built in controls to only allow valid geometry and domains to control attribute integrity.</logic>
<complete>This theme is current to date of publication.</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>Generally the source information used to record spatial locations are from: 1) on-screen digitizing with a georeferenced topographic or image background; or 2) GPS field collected positions.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>This data was published using Feature Manipulation Engine Software. The spatial features were extracted from the transactional database, manipulated to meet the desired output format and published to the target feature class. This data was migrated from the CDW. The spatial features were projected and imported into the target feature class.</procdesc>
<procdate>20151227</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>451</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.BdyDesg_LSRS_Wilderness</enttypl>
<enttypd>A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
<enttypds>http://support.esri.com/en/knowledgebase/GISDictionary/term/feature%20class</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>WILDERNESSID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Unique identifier generated by Oracle sequence or SYS_GUID() function.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unique identifier.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>WILDERNESSNAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of a specific Wilderness Area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Proper name.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AREAID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Legacy code associated with wilderness area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service, FS National Wilderness Coordinator</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>3-digit internal identifier.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>BOUNDARYSTATUS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Legal status of the Regulated Use boundary. Choices include: Final or Provisional, Subject to Change</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>Final</edomv>
<edomvd>Boundary is finalized</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Provisional</edomv>
<edomvd>Boundary is provisional</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Subject to Change</edomv>
<edomvd>Boundary is subject to change</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GIS_ACRES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The area of the feature in acres, calculated using a projected surface computation. A NAD 83, USA Contiguous Albers Equal Area Conic projection was used for Regions 1-9, and NAD 83, Alaska Albers for Region 10.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The area of a feature in acres.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>WID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The Wilderness ID is a unique identifier that connects a USFS published Wilderness Area to additional information at wilderness.net.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unique identifier generated by Oracle sequence or SYS_GUID() function.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
<distliab>The U.S. Forest Service makes no warranty, express or implied, nor assumes any liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness, or utility of these geospatial data or for the improper or incorrect use of those data. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible for verifying the limitations of the geospatial data and for using the data accordingly.</distliab>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20250929</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
