<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<pubdate>20251203</pubdate>
<pubtime>145957</pubtime>
<title>BdyDesg_Disaster_Recov_Event</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>Spatial data is collected by the National Disaster Recovery Team from each unit point of contact. The spatial locations are pulled from fire occurrence and perimeter datasets, FEMA, States, and local unit disaster response assessments. The polygons are then processed through intersections with geopolitical boundaries such as states, counties, and congressional districts as well as administrative boundaries such as regions and forests.</abstract>
<purpose>This is an agency-wide disaster recovery geospatial dataset that will support communications and stakeholder engagement, delineate where disaster recovery projects align with other priorities such as active management and recreation. The data in this dataset supports standardized reporting and resource optimization.</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<rngdates>
<begdate>2022</begdate>
<enddate>present</enddate>
</rngdates>
</timeinfo>
<current>Unknown</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>In work</progress>
<update>Daily</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-156.687752772</westbc>
<eastbc>-65.25905421</eastbc>
<northbc>48.999907029</northbc>
<southbc>18.281028699</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
</theme>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
<country>US</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<native>
</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<logic>Data was collected from fire points and polygons, FEMA boundaries, and point locations of disasters. The attribute information is checked against the workplan.</logic>
<complete>Data completeness of the National Disaster Recovery Events dataset reflects the disaster information provided to the national Disaster Action Recovery Team from the Strategic Planning, Budget, and Accountability director area. The data that is currently included in this dataset are for events that are currrently funded for disaster recovery work. The DART team will continue to update this dataset as additional disaster events are provided. For the purpose of this data layer, unfunded events were excluded at this time but will be added in the future. PII has been excluded from this dataset and at this time it is for internal use only. </complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>This data comes from accross the nation, from forests and regions, from other agencies, and therefore the horizonal accuracy is variable.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Compliation of data sources including, but not limited to, Forest Service internal fire perimeters, FEMA data sources for hurricanes and floods, and locally derived spatial data. The polygons are then processed through intersections with geopolitical boundaries such as states, counties, and congressional districts as well as administrative boundaries such as regions and forests.. </procdesc>
<procdate>20250915</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>Complete chain</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>82</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.BdyDesg_Disaster_Recov_Event</enttypl>
<enttypd>Feature class: A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
<enttypds>ESRI GIS Dictionary</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>UNIQUE_DISASTERS_ID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Unique identifier for the feature.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unique ID</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DISASTERCATEGORY</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Whether the event is fire or non-fire related.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>Fire</edomv>
<edomvd>The event is related to a wildfire.</edomvd>
<edomvds>US Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Non-Fire</edomv>
<edomvd>The event is non-fire related.</edomvd>
<edomvds>US Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DISASTERTYPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The type of natural hazard as defined by the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>FEMA</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>Avalanche </edomv>
<edomvd>An Avalanche is a mass of snow in swift motion traveling down a mountainside. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Coastal Flooding </edomv>
<edomvd>Coastal Flooding is when water inundates or covers normally dry coastal land as a result of high or rising tides or storm surges. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Cold Wave </edomv>
<edomvd>A Cold Wave is a rapid fall in temperature within 24 hours and extreme low temperatures for an extended period. The temperatures classified as a Cold Wave are dependent on the location and defined by the local NWS weather forecast office. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Drought </edomv>
<edomvd>A Drought is a deficiency of precipitation over an extended period of time resulting in a water shortage. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Earthquake </edomv>
<edomvd>An Earthquake is a shaking of the earth’s surface by energy waves emitted by slowly moving tectonic plates overcoming friction with one another underneath the earth’s surface. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Hail </edomv>
<edomvd>Hail is a form of precipitation that occurs during thunderstorms when raindrops, in extremely cold areas of the atmosphere, freeze into balls of ice before falling towards the earth’s surface. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Heat Wave </edomv>
<edomvd>A Heat Wave is a period of abnormally and uncomfortably hot and unusually humid weather typically lasting two or more days with temperatures outside the historical averages for a given area. The temperatures classified as a Heat Wave are dependent on the location and defined by the local NWS weather forecast office. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Hurricane </edomv>
<edomvd>A Hurricane is a tropical cyclone or localized, low-pressure weather system that has organized thunderstorms but no front (a boundary separating two air masses of different densities) and maximum sustained winds of at least 74 miles per hour (mph). The Hurricane data also include tropical storms for which wind speeds range from 39 to 74 mph. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Ice Storm </edomv>
<edomvd>An Ice Storm is a freezing rain situation (rain that freezes on surface contact) with significant ice accumulations of 0.25 inches or greater. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Landslide </edomv>
<edomvd>A Landslide is the movement of a mass of rock, debris, or earth down a slope. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Lightning </edomv>
<edomvd>Lightning is a visible electrical discharge or spark of electricity in the atmosphere between clouds, the air, and/or the ground often produced by a thunderstorm. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Riverine Flooding </edomv>
<edomvd>Riverine Flooding is when streams and rivers exceed the capacity of their natural or constructed channels to accommodate water flow and water overflows the banks, spilling into adjacent low-lying, dry land. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Strong Wind </edomv>
<edomvd>Strong Wind consists of damaging winds, often originating from thunderstorms, that are classified as exceeding 58 mph. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Tornado </edomv>
<edomvd>A Tornado is a narrow, violently rotating column of air that extends from the base of a thunderstorm to the ground and is visible only if it forms a condensation funnel made up of water droplets, dust, and debris. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Tsunami </edomv>
<edomvd>A Tsunami is a wave or series of waves generated by an earthquake, landslide, volcanic eruption, or even a large meteor hitting the ocean and causing a rise or mounding of water at the ocean surface. A Tsunami can travel across the open ocean at about 500 mph and slow down to about 30 mph as it approaches land, causing it to grow significantly in height. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Volcanic Activity </edomv>
<edomvd>Volcanic Activity occurs via vents that act as a conduit between the Earth’s surface and inner layers, and erupt gas, molten rock, and volcanic ash when gas pressure and buoyancy drive molten rock upward and through zones of weakness in the Earth’s crust. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Wildfire </edomv>
<edomvd>A Wildfire is an unplanned fire burning in natural or wildland areas, such as forest, shrub lands, grasslands, or prairies. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Winter Weather </edomv>
<edomvd>Winter Weather consists of winter storm events in which the main types of precipitation are snow, sleet, or freezing rain. </edomvd>
<edomvds>Federal Emergency Management Agency</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DISASTERTYPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The type of natural hazard as defined by the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>Flooding/Wind </edomv>
<edomvd>Flooding occurs when water inundates and overflows normally dry areas of land. Strong winds occurs when there are strong damaging winds not related to a tornado. This category is used by USFS SPBA. </edomvd>
<edomvds>US Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Snow Pack or Rain </edomv>
<edomvd>Snow Pack is  seasonal accumulation of slow-melting packed snow, and Rain as a hazard occurs when heavy or unexpected rain and/or thunderstorms that cause damage to the area. This category is used by USFS SPBA. </edomvd>
<edomvds>US Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>LEGISLATION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The legislation that grants approprations for disaster relief.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>American Relief Act of 2025</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>WORKPLANDISASTEREVENTNAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the event assigned in workplan.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Workplan Name</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DRTDISASTEREVENTNAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the event assigend by the Disaster Recovery Team and used in disaster recovery tracking.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>DRT Name</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DISASTERYEAR</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The year of the disaster event.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Disaster Year</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DISASTERSTARTDATE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The start date of the disaster.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Start Date</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>DISASTERDESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The description of the disaster and/or event.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Description</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FUNDED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The determination if the event has been funded for disaster recovery.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>Funded</edomv>
<edomvd>Identifies that the event has been funded for disaster recovery.</edomvd>
<edomvds>US Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Unfunded</edomv>
<edomvd>Identifies that the event has not been funded for disaster recovery.</edomvd>
<edomvds>US Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>POLYGONTYPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The type of polygon used to display the disaster event.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>Point Buffer</edomv>
<edomvd>The spatial representation of the disaster event was created by buffering the point location by 1 meter.</edomvd>
<edomvds>US Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Event Perimeter</edomv>
<edomvd>The spatial polygon was pulled from an event perimeter.</edomvd>
<edomvds>US Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Forest Boundary</edomv>
<edomvd>The spatial polygon was identified as the administrative forest boundary. </edomvd>
<edomvds>US Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SPATIALSOURCE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The source for the event polygon.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Source</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GIS_ACRES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The area of the feature in acres, calculated in North American Albers Equal Area Conic projection (NAD83) meters and then converted to acres with the formula AreaMeters * 0.0002471054.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Acres</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Esri field of boundary area in coordinate system units</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Esri field of boundary length in coordinate system units</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Esri field of boundary length in coordinate system units</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Esri field of boundary length in coordinate system units </udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20251203</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
<country>US</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
