<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>U.S. Forest Service</origin>
<pubdate>20220531</pubdate>
<pubtime>143635</pubtime>
<title>S_USA.BdyPlan_RoadlessArea_2008_ID</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<onlink>http://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/datasets.php</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>The RoadlessArea_ID_2008 feature class describes the boundaries of Roadless Areas designated by the Idaho Roadless Rule of 2008 and managed by the U.S. Forest Service. The final rule reflects the views and concerns of thousands of people who expressed interest during the rule-making process, which ran from October 2006 to October 2008. The public comment period generated 38,000 comments. The Idaho Roadless Rule takes a balanced approach, recognizing both local and national interests. Five management themes have been established (and are identified in the MgmtClassification attribute) that provide prohibitions, with exceptions or conditioned permissions, governing timber cutting, removing and selling, road construction and reconstruction, and certain mineral activities. These management themes are: Wild Land Recreation, Special Areas of Historic or Tribal Significance, Primitive, Backcountry Restoration, and General Forest, Rangeland, and Grassland. Each theme provides management direction that varies from most restrictive to least restrictive and provides roadless character that varies from higher quality to lower quality. Forest Plan Special Areas are also identified, where management of the area is according to Forest Plan direction, not the Idaho Roadless Rule. These special areas include items such as wild and scenic river corridors, research natural areas, etc. This dataset is a compilation of the most up to date Roadless areas from the National Forests in Idaho. This dataset was compiled by taking the roadless area boundaries from each of the National Forests in Idaho and adding the management area prescription boundaries from each forest. For some forests both the existing forest plan management prescription layer and a "proposed" prescriptions boundaries were used. See the list of these Forests in the metadata for the each forest. Date of last update Date of last update is captured in the Lineage section.</abstract>
<purpose>The RoadlessArea_ID_2008 feature class describes the boundaries of Roadless Areas designated by the Idaho Roadless Rule of 2008 and managed by the U.S. Forest Service. The Idaho Roadless Rule provides management direction for conserving and managing approximately 9.3 million acres of Idaho Roadless Areas on National Forest System lands and replaces the roadless areas identified in the 2001 Roadless Area Conservation Rule. The Chief of the Forest Service may modify or make administrative corrections to the boundaries of any Idaho Roadless Areas after public notice and comment and coordination with the state. This data reflects the selected alternative of the Idaho Roadless Final Environmental Impact Statement (FEIS).</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20150218</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>publication date</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>As needed</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-117.034085</westbc>
<eastbc>-111.042990</eastbc>
<northbc>48.999594</northbc>
<southbc>41.993959</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>Kootenai National Forest</themekey>
<themekey>Caribou National Forest</themekey>
<themekey>Sawtooth National Forest</themekey>
<themekey>Payette National Forest</themekey>
<themekey>Idaho</themekey>
<themekey>Challis National Forest</themekey>
<themekey>Clearwater National Forest</themekey>
<themekey>Boise National Forest</themekey>
<themekey>Targhee National Forest</themekey>
<themekey>Wallowa-Whitman National Forest</themekey>
<themekey>Idaho Roadless Area boundaries</themekey>
<themekey>Salmon National Forest</themekey>
<themekey>Idaho Panhandle National Forest</themekey>
</theme>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>U.S. Forest Service Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<datacred>Data was compiled from the 11 National Forests in Idaho: Boise, Caribou, Challis, Clearwater, Idaho Panhandle, Kootenai, Payette, Salmon, Sawtooth,Targhee, and Wallowa-Whitman.</datacred>
<native>Esri ArcGIS 13.3.4.52636</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<logic>None</logic>
<complete>None</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>Generally the source information used to record spatial locations are from: 1) on-screen digitizing with a georeferenced topographic or image background; or 2) GPS field collected positions.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Update: R04 GIS Lab; T. Rhodes 7/2014; Idaho Panhandle National Forest boundary modifications and corrections resulting from June 11, 2014 Federal Register notification - http://http://www.fs.usda.gov/Internet/FSE_DOCUMENTS/stelprd3805148.pdf have been completed on this dataset. The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), Forest Service is modifying the boundaries for the Big Creek, Grandmother Mountain, Pinchot Butte, Roland Point, and Wonderful Peak Idaho Roadless Areas on the Idaho Panhandle National Forests to include lands acquired within and/or adjacent to these roadless areas. In addition, the Forest Service is correcting mapping errors involving Forest Plan Special Areas in the Salmo-Priest and Upper Priest Idaho Roadless Areas. For more information, please visit: http://www.fs.usda.gov/detail/roadless/idahoroadlessrule/?cid=stelprdb5382399 Line work that was used to create the August 38, 2012 proposal maps as well as the current authoritative land ownership data were referenced for the modifications/corrections. Using current ownership data did result in a 3 acre difference on Grandmother Mountain.</procdesc>
<procdate>20120701</procdate>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>UPDATE: R04 GIS Lab; T.Rhoades 6/2014: To prepare these data for inclusion into the Forest Service Enterprise Data Warehouse (EDW), the data were modified to meet EDW standards. The following changes were made to the original fields: ROADLESS_NAME: renamed to RoadlessAreaName; FOREST: renamed to ForestPlanningUnitName; MIRR_022011 (alias FEIS_SELECTED_ALTERNATIVE): Renamed to MgmtClassification; DATE_OF_LAST_UPDATE: field dropped. This field was tracking the Payette corrections and splitting roadless areas into multiple polygons. This information was deemed unnecessary, the field was dropped and polygons merged so official acres could be coded on the data. The following records were deemed unnecessary to the data and therefore deleted: ROADLESS_NAME in ('NOT A ROADLESS AREA', 'NOT FS', 'PVT'); MIRR_022011 = 'NOT FS' The following fields were added to the data: MgmtClassificationCode; RegionCode_ca2008; RegionName_ca2008; ForestCode_ca2008; ForestName_ca2008; ForestOrgCode_ca2008; StateCode; StateName; Acres</procdesc>
<procdate>20140601</procdate>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>UPDATE: R04 GIS Lab - T.Rhoades 9/2015 ===&gt;&gt; Caribou-Targhee National Forest boundary modifications and corrections resulting from July8, 2015 Federal Register notification - http://www.fs.usda.gov/Internet/FSE_DOCUMENTS/stelprd3846255.pdf have been completed on this dataset. The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), Forest Service is modifying the West Mink Idaho Roadless Area boundary on the Caribou-Targhee National Forest to relocate and expand the Gibson Jack Trailhead. For more information, please visit: http://www.fs.usda.gov/detail/roadless/idahoroadlessrule/?cid=stelprdb5382399 Linework that was provided by the forest was used in the modification.</procdesc>
<procdate>20150918</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>547</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.BdyPlan_RoadlessArea_2008_ID</enttypl>
<enttypd>A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
<enttypds>http://support.esri.com/en/knowledgebase/GISDictionary/term/feature%20class</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ROADLESSAREANAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The official name of the roadless area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The name of the roadless area.  For example:  "Grandmother Mountain."</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MGMTCLASSIFICATIONCODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The code describing the management classification of the roadless area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>BCR</edomv>
<edomvd>Backcountry Restoration</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>GFRG</edomv>
<edomvd>General Forest, Rangeland, and Grassland</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>SAHTS</edomv>
<edomvd>Special Area of Historic or Tribal Significance </edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>P</edomv>
<edomvd>Primitive</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>WLR</edomv>
<edomvd>Wild Land Recreation</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MGMTCLASSIFICATION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The management classification designated to the roadless area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>Backcountry Restoration</edomv>
<edomvd>Backcountry Restoration</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>General Forest, Rangeland, and Grassland </edomv>
<edomvd>General Forest, Rangeland, and Grassland </edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Special Area of Historic or Tribal Significance</edomv>
<edomvd>Special Area of Historic or Tribal Significance</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Primitive</edomv>
<edomvd>Primitive</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Forest Plan Special Area</edomv>
<edomvd>Forest Plan Special Area</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Wild Land Recreation</edomv>
<edomvd>Wild Land Recreation</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>REGIONCODE_CA2008</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The code for the  U.S. Forest Service Region in which this roadless area exists, at the time of the roadless rule (2008)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Two digit Region Code.  For example "01" for Northern Region.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>REGIONNAME_CA2008</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the U.S. Forest Service Region in which this roadless area exists at the time of the roadless rule (2008)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The Region Name.  For example, Northern or Intermountain</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FORESTCODE_CA2008</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The code of the National Forest in which this roadless area exists, at the time of the roadless rule (2008).</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The two digit forest code.  For example 13 for Salmon-Challis National Forest</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FORESTNAME_CA2008</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the National Forest in which this roadless area exists, at the time of the roadless rule (2008).</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The forest name.  For example:  Salmon-Challis National Forest</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FORESTORGCODE_CA2008</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The concatenation of the region and forest code of the National Forest in which the roadless area exists, at the time of the roadless rule (2008)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The four digit organization code for the National Forest in the format RRFF where RR is the region code and FF is the forest code.  For example, 0413 for the Salmon-Challis National Forest in the Intermountain Region</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FORESTPLANNINGUNITNAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the Forest Planning Unit whose Forest Plan was in force during the designation of the roadless area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The name of the National Forest at the time of the last Forest Plan.  For example, Challis.  This may be different than the Forest Name circa 2008.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STATECODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The two character state abbreviation for the state in which the roadless area occurs</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Census</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The two digit state abbreviation of the state in which the roadless area is located.  For example AL for Alabama</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STATENAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the state in which the roadless area occurs.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Census</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The name of the state in which the roadless area occurs.  For example, Alabama</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACRES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The official size of the roadless area in acres.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Number of acres in the roadless area.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20250415</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>U.S. Forest Service Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
<metuc>This product is reproduced from geospatial information prepared by the U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service. By removing the contents of this package or taking receipt of these files via electronic file transfer methods, you understand that the data stored on this media is in draft condition. Represented features may not be in an accurate geographic location. The Forest Service makes no expressed or implied warranty, including warranty of merchantability and fitness, with respect to the character, function, or capabilities of the data or their appropriateness for any user's purposes. The Forest Service reserves the right to correct, update, modify, or replace this geospatial information based on new inventories, new or revised information, and as required by policy or regulation in conjunction with other federal, state or local public agencies or the public in general. Previous recipients of the products may not be notified unless required by policy or regulation.</metuc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
