<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<pubdate>20180513</pubdate>
<title>S_USA.Rec_RecArea_Activities_V</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>This dataset contains the recreation opportunity information that the Forest Service collects through the Recreation Portal and shares with the public on http://www.recreation.gov, the Forest Service World Wide Web pages (http://www.fs.fed.us/) and the Interactive Visitor Map. This recreation data contains detailed descriptions of recreational sites, areas, activities &amp;amp; facilities. This published dataset consists of one point feature class for recreational areas, one spatial view and three related tables such as activities, facilities &amp;amp; rec area advisories. The purpose of each related table is described belowRECAREAACTIVITIES: This related table contains information about the activities that are associated with the rec area.RECAREAFACILITIES: This related table contains information about the amenities that are associated with the rec area.RECAREAADVISORIES: This table contains events, news, alerts and warnings that are associated with the rec area.RECAREAACTIVITIES_V: This spatial view/feature class is generated by joining the RECAREAACTIVITIES table to the RECREATION OPPORTUNITIES Feature Class. Please note that the RECAREAID is the unique identifier present in point feature class and in the related tables as well. The RECAREAID is used as foreign key to access relate records.This published data is updated nightly from an XML feed maintained by the CIO Rec Portal team. This data is intended for public use and distribution.</abstract>
<purpose>This dataset contains the recreation opportunity information that the Forest Service collects through the Recreation Portal and shares with the public on http://www.recreation.gov, the Forest Service World Wide Web pages (http://www.fs.fed.us/) and the Interactive Visitor Map. This recreation data contains detailed descriptions of recreational sites, activities, facilities &amp; advisories. This published dataset consists of one point feature class, one spatial view and three related tables.</purpose>
</descript>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-149.985000</westbc>
<eastbc>-65.729444</eastbc>
<northbc>61.082222</northbc>
<southbc>18.267429</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>This data is intended for public use and distribution. The Forest Service uses the most current and complete data available. GIS data and product accuracy may vary. They may be developed from sources of differing accuracy; accurate only at certain scales; based on modeling or interpretation; incomplete while being created or revised; etc. Using GIS products for purposes other than those for which they were created, may yield inaccurate or misleading results. The Forest Service reserves the right to correct, update, modify or replace GIS products without notification.</useconst>
<datacred>USDA Forest Service</datacred>
<native>Esri ArcGIS 13.3.0.52636</native>
</idinfo>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>52479</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.Rec_RecArea_Activities_V</enttypl>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RECAREAURL</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Hyperlink to Forest Service world wide web recreation portal web page.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RESERVATION_INFO</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Information about reservation requirements or options for the public.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OPERATIONAL_HOURS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Times of day when the area is open for use by the public.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FORESTNAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Name of the national forest.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RECAREANAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Name of the Rec Area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FEEDESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Fees charged to the public to access or use this area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>LONGITUDE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Longitude (location of area)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MARKERACTIVITY</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The MarkerType chosen to represent an area corresponds to this activity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MARKERTYPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>This is a URL to the graphic chosen by the field to represent the area on maps. The marker corresponds with an activity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACTIVITYID</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PARENTACTIVITYID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The Parent Activity ID</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACTIVITYNAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Name of the activity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>LATITUDE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Latitude (location of area)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OPEN_SEASON_END</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Seasonal information about when the area is closed to public use</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACTIVITYDESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Description of the Activity at the area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MARKERACTIVITYGROUP</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Activities in the Portal are grouped into activity groups. This is the activity group for the activity that corresponds to the chose marker.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RESTRICTIONS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Limitations and restrictions affecting the public's ability to access and use this area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OPEN_SEASON_START</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Seasonal information about when the area becomes available for use by the public.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RECAREAID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Rec area unique identifier</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RECAREADESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Description of the Rec Area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SPOTLIGHTDISPLAY</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ATTRACTIONDISPLAY</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACCESSIBILITY</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OPENSTATUS</attrlabl>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PARENTACTIVITYNAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The Parent activity name.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20250318</metd>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
