<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>U.S. Forest Service</origin>
<pubdate>20251029</pubdate>
<pubtime>200047</pubtime>
<title>S_USA.Rec_RecOpportunities</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<onlink>http://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/datasets.php</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>This dataset contains the recreation site opportunity information that the Forest Service collects through the Recreation Portal and shares with the public on the Forest Service World Wide Web pages www.fs.usda.gov, the Recreation Information Database (RIDB), the Enterprise Data Warehouse (EDW), and the Interactive Visitor Map. This recreation database contains descriptions of recreational sites, areas, activities and facilities.</abstract>
<purpose>Recreation opportunities are point locations of recreational site activities available to visitors and populates the Forest Service websites at www.fs.usda.gov, and the interactive visitor map at https://www.fs.usda.gov/ivm/.</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20160101</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>publication date</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>As needed</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-149.985000</westbc>
<eastbc>-65.729444</eastbc>
<northbc>61.082222</northbc>
<southbc>18.267429</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
<themekey>society</themekey>
</theme>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<datacred>USDA Forest Service</datacred>
<native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.9.1.28388</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<logic>This published dataset consists of one point feature class for recreational areas, one spatial view and three related tables such as activities, facilities and rec area advisories. The purpose of each related table is described below. RECAREAACTIVITIES: This related table contains information about the activities that are associated with the rec area. RECAREAFACILITIES: This related table contains information about the amenities that are associated with the rec area. RECAREAADVISORIES: This table contains events, news, alerts and warnings that are associated with the rec area. RECAREAACTIVITIES_V: This spatial view/feature class is generated by joining the RECAREAACTIVITIES table to the RECREATION OPPORTUNITIES Feature Class. Please note that the RECAREAID is the unique identifier present in point feature class and in the related tables as well. The RECAREAID is used as a foreign key to access related records. This published data is updated nightly from an XML feed maintained by the CIO Rec Portal team. This data is intended for public use and distribution.</logic>
<complete>Trails are excluded because this dataset is formatted as points and trails are linear. Data is generalized locations placed near the major access point of the recreation site or the center point if there are multiple major access points.</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>Generally the source information used to record spatial locations are from: 1) on-screen digitizing with a georeferenced topographic or image background; or 2) GPS field collected positions.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>1. Recreation point data in the Forest Service Enterprise Data Warehouse (EDW) are updated daily from the Forest Service Recreation Portal. 2. Data are delivered from the Recreation Portal through an XML document feed located at http://www.fs.usda.gov/Internet/extract/EDW.zip 3. Data are spatially enabled into point data using the Latitude/Longitude fields in the XML feed. 4. Recreation data from the XML feed where the RECAREANAME field contains the word Trail but not TrailHead are not included in the EDW Recreational point data. 5. This data is also re-purposed into markers and links for the Interactive Visitor Map.</procdesc>
<procdate>20210101</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>14469</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.Rec_RecOpportunities</enttypl>
<enttypd>A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
<enttypds>http://support.esri.com/en/knowledgebase/GISDictionary/term/feature%20class</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RESTRICTIONS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Limitations and restrictions affecting the public's ability to access and use this area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual description of restrictions.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RECAREADESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Description of the Rec Area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual description of the recreation area, often in HTML.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FORESTNAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Forests are subdivisions of regions and can be found by drilling through regions on https://www.fs.usda.gov/organization.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Name of Forest associated with management of Recreation Site.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MARKERACTIVITY</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The MarkerType chosen to represent an area corresponds to this activity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual description of the activity occurring at the marker.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OPEN_SEASON_END</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Seasonal information about when the area is closed to public use</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Various representations of season end date. Valid examples are a month, a holiday, or "Year-Round"</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>INFRA_CN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Number assigned to the Recreation Area from the Infra database.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Infra database identifier</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OPEN_SEASON_START</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Seasonal information about when the area becomes available for use by the public.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Various representations of season start date. Valid examples are a month, a holiday, or "Year-Round"</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ATTRACTIONDISPLAY</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Enables or disables a link to be displayed on the "attraction" portion of the home webpage.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>N</edomv>
<edomvd>No</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Y</edomv>
<edomvd>Yes</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>LONGITUDE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Longitude (location of area)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Longitudinal locational information in decimal degrees.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RECPORTAL_UNIT_KEY</attrlabl>
<attrdef>National Forest Areas</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Parent recreation facility or forest.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MARKERTYPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>This is a URL to the graphic chosen by the field to represent the area on maps. The marker corresponds with an activity.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>URL to the marker graphic for the recreation area.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RESERVATION_INFO</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Information about reservation requirements or options for the public.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual description of reservation information. May include link to online reservation site.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACCESSIBILITY</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Information about accessible features within the recreation area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Information regarding accessible or non-accessible features within the recreation area, often in HTML. May include description of "No accessible features" or similar.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OPENSTATUS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The usable condition of the Rec Area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The usable condition of the recreation area, e.g. open, closed, temporarily closed, unknown, etc.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SPOTLIGHTDISPLAY</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Enables or disables a link to be displayed on the "spotlight" portion of the home webpage.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>N</edomv>
<edomvd>No</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Y</edomv>
<edomvd>Yes</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RECAREANAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Name of the Rec Area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Name of Recreation Area as described for the public facing websites.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FORESTORGCODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The full organizational code of an administrative unit.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The full organizational code of an administrative unit.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>LATITUDE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Latitude (location of area)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Latitudinal locational information in decimal degrees.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RECAREAURL</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Hyperlink to Forest Service world wide web recreation portal web page.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>URL to recreation portal web page.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OPERATIONAL_HOURS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Times of day when the area is open for use by the public.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual description of publicly accessible hours.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RECAREAID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Rec area unique identifier</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Unique identifier.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MARKERACTIVITYGROUP</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Activities in the Portal are grouped into activity groups. This is the activity group for the activity that corresponds to the chosen marker.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual description of the parent group for activities occurring at the marker. For instance, day hiking would be in the parent group of hiking.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FEEDESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Fees charged to the public to access or use this area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Textual description of fees associated with the recreation site.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
<distliab>The U.S. Forest Service makes no warranty, express or implied, nor assumes any liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness, or utility of these geospatial data or for the improper or incorrect use of those data. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible for verifying the limitations of the geospatial data and for using the data accordingly.</distliab>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20250327</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
