<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xsl/fgdc-details.xsl"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>USDA Forest Service - Pacific Southwest Region - Remote Sensing Lab</origin>
        <pubdate>20180322</pubdate>
        <pubtime>152713</pubtime>
        <title>Existing Vegetation CALVEG Zones</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>McClellan, CA</pubplace>
          <publish>Remote Sensing Lab</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>http://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/datasets.php</onlink>
        <onlink>http://www.fs.fed.us/land/pubs/ecoregions/intro.html</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This polygon layer consists of boundaries for the ecological tile units and CALVEG (Classification and Assessment with Landsat of Visible Ecological Groupings) zone units currently being used to tile the EVEG (existing vegetation) dataset. Selected lines were added from the CalWater watershed layer where finer tile divisions were needed. Additionally, attributes from Ecological Units of California (Ecological Domain, Division, Province, Section and Subsection) have been incorporated into this layer. (see Procedures and Citation sections).</abstract>
      <purpose>This layer was developed as a tiling system to serve out logical portions of vegetation data for use in land management issues such as forest-wide planning efforts, wildlife habitat mapping and fire risk assessment.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Refer to the Process Description section of the metadata for the Procedures Used Worklog.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20171116</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>20140601</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-124.416283</westbc>
        <eastbc>-114.129818</eastbc>
        <northbc>42.556717</northbc>
        <southbc>32.535034</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>map tiles</themekey>
        <themekey>ecoregions</themekey>
        <themekey>eveg</themekey>
        <themekey>zones</themekey>
        <themekey>calveg</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>biota</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>Not recommended for use at scales greater than 1:24000. The Forest Service uses the most current and complete data available. GIS data and product accuracy may vary. They may be developed from sources of differing accuracy; accurate only at certain scales; based on modeling or interpretation; incomplete while being created or revised; etc. Using GIS products for purposes other than those for which they were created, may yield inaccurate or misleading results. The Forest Service reserves the right to correct, update, modify or replace GIS products without notification.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntemail>data@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.5.1.7333</native>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>USDA Forest Service, Region 5, Remote Sensing Lab</origin>
        <pubdate>20180322</pubdate>
        <title>CALVEG 2000</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Bailey, R.G.</origin>
        <pubdate>20180322</pubdate>
        <title>Descriptions of the Ecoregions of the United States</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Goudey, C.B., and D.W. Smith, eds</origin>
        <pubdate>20180322</pubdate>
        <title>Ecological Units of California: Subsections</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Cleland, D.T.; Freeouf, J. A.; Nowacki, G.J.; Carpenter, C; Keys, J.E; McNab, W.H. Subregions of the conterminous United States. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service</origin>
        <pubdate>20180322</pubdate>
        <title>National Hierarchical Framework of Ecological Units (Ecomap)</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>Data entry is accomplished by authorized Forest Service personnel through a web application behind the U.S. Forest Service firewall and is restricted by access requirement protocols.</logic>
    <complete>Data is complete as of publication.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The horizontal geospatial positioning accuracy for EVMid (Midlevel Existing Vegetation): +- 166 ft. For more information see Geospatial Positioning Accuracy Standards Part 3: National Standard for Spatial Data Accuracy (FGDC-STD-007.3-1998 (FGDC 1998)): https://www.fgdc.gov/standards/projects/FGDC-standards-projects/accuracy/part3/chapter3. Minimum standards for source scale geo-registration is 1:100,000.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Initial coverage input.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20000301</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Edited for merge between tile 66 and tile 67 CALTILE99_2 (shayes, PMR) 3/2/00 - edited for merge between tile 64 and tile 17 CALTILE99_1 (shayes, PMR)</procdesc>
        <procdate>20000309</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Name changed to reflect extent of coverage CALTILE99_3 (shayes, PMR)</procdesc>
        <procdate>20011024</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Basic data for the vegetation mapping was raster data (LANDSAT TM data). In order to make seamless compilation of the TM data, the old polygon coverage of tiles was rasterized and converted back to polygon. This was done so, that the edges of the tile boundaries were represented as pixels rather than simple line features. R5TILE99_3 (cclark, GDM)</procdesc>
        <procdate>20020301</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The original tiles in R5TILE99_A were further divided into smaller units to accommodate increased vegetation layer file sizes. Tile boundaries were re-rasterized to five meters in order to match the resolution of new vegetation map layers. R5TILE99_A (pdaliparthi, GDM)</procdesc>
        <procdate>20040601</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Coverage exported as feature class to RSL SDE database. R5TILE04_1 (pdaliparthi,Softsol)</procdesc>
        <procdate>20050701</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Attributes and linework from EcoregionsCalifornia layer used to incorporate Ecoregion attributes into the original tile/zone index as follows: 1) CalvegTilesAndZones feature dataset split into two pieces due to ArcInfo size limitations. Converted to coverage and processed using an ArcInfo aml to union it with EcoregionsCalifornia and eliminate unneeded slivers. 2) Some areas outside CA boundary were not contained in the EcoregionsCalifornia layer, therefore additional linework and attributes pulled from EcoregionsUSA (see Citation). 3) Two pieces converted back to features classes, appended and dissolved to eliminate redundant linework. *Note - Polygons exist along the coast of California as buffers created in the original CalvegTilesAndZones. These will have no coding for Ecoregion attributes. CalvegTilesAndZones (tlindemann, GD).</procdesc>
        <procdate>20060131</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Tile 5 split into smaller sections: 5A and 5B CalvegTiles_Ecoregions (cclark, GD)</procdesc>
        <procdate>20070401</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Linework and attributing updated to match changes made in EcoregionsCalifornia07_1 layer per updates on the national EcoMap07 map: EcoMap07: Cleland, D.T.; Freeouf, J.A.; Keys, J.E., Jr.; Nowacki, G.J.; Carpenter, C; McNab, W.H. 2007. Ecological Subregions: Sections and Subsections of the Conterminous United States [1:3,500,000] [CD-ROM]. Sloan, A.M., cartog. Gen. Tech. Report WO-76. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service. CalvegTilesEcoregions06_2 (cclark, GD)</procdesc>
        <procdate>20080901</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Subsection M261Em boundary altered at junction of Tile 20 and Tile 67B to more accurately match the division in EcoregionsCalifornia07_1. This division had inaccurately followed a National Forest Administrative boundary. CalvegTilesEcoregions07_1 (cclark, GD)</procdesc>
        <procdate>20081201</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>CTrillo RSL Updated the attributes for two polygons in the Northeast portion of the CalvegTilesEcoregions layer near the Modoc NF. The attributes for the two Surprise Valley polygons had been mistakenly attributed as High Desert-Wetlands (342Bi). The Modoc NF discovered the error and the polygons have been changed back to the correct label of Surprise Valley (342Ba). CalvegTilesEcoregions07_2 (cclark, GD)</procdesc>
        <procdate>20081230</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>cclark, GD Correction made in Section 263A (Northern California Coast Section). Subsection corrected to 263Ad (Wiregrass Ridge) from previous mislabel of M261Bb (Central Franciscan) CalvegTilesEcoregions07_3</procdesc>
        <procdate>20100216</procdate>
      </procstep>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>cclark, TT Subsection 261Ad (East Bay Terraces and Alluvium) reintroduced into East Bay area and Subsection 261Ai (San Francisco Peninsula) reintroduced on the SF Peninsula per the work of Ecological Subregions of California: Miles, S.R.; Goudey, C.B.; Alexander, E. B.; Sawyer, J. O. 1997 Buffers created in initial dataset on California coast split and attributed to match coincident polygon. CalvegTilesEcoregions07_4</procdesc>
        <procdate>20140320</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>340</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>8.98315284119521e-009</latres>
        <longres>8.98315284119521e-009</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal Degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>S_USA.EV_CalvegZones_Ecoregions</enttypl>
        <enttypd>A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>http://support.esri.com/en/other-resources/gis-dictionary/term/feature%20class</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ECOREGION_DOMAIN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Ecosystem of related climates, differentiated based on precipitation and temperature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USDA Forest Service, Goudey and Smith (1994), Ecological Units of California-Subsections: https://www.fs.usda.gov/detail/r5/landmanagement/resourcemanagement/?cid=stelprdb5365219</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>FRDB (Forest Resource Database) Table 101: http://www.fs.usda.gov/detail/r5/landmanagement/resourcemanagement/?cid=fsbdev3_048042</codesetn>
            <codesets>USFS Region 5</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ECOREGION_DIVISION</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Subdivisions of climates within Domains, differentiated based on precipitation levels and patterns as well as temperature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USDA Forest Service, Goudey and Smith (1994), Ecological Units of California-Subsections</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>FRDB Table 102: http://www.fs.usda.gov/detail/r5/landmanagement/resourcemanagement/?cid=fsbdev3_048043</codesetn>
            <codesets>USFS Region 5</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ECOREGION_PROVINCE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Divisions are subdivided into Provinces, which are differentiated based on vegetation or other natural land covers.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USDA Forest Service, Goudey and Smith (1994), Ecological Units of California-Subsections</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>FRDB Table 103a: http://www.fs.usda.gov/detail/r5/landmanagement/resourcemanagement/?cid=fsbdev3_048051</codesetn>
            <codesets>USFS Region 5</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ECOREGION_SECTION</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Subdivisions of Provinces based on terrain features.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USDA Forest Service, Goudey and Smith (1994), Ecological Units of California-Subsections</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>FRDB Table 104a: http://www.fs.usda.gov/detail/r5/landmanagement/resourcemanagement/?cid=fsbdev3_048066</codesetn>
            <codesets>USFS Service Region 5</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ECOREGION_SUBSECTION</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>More refined divisions of Sections based on terrain features. From the Ecological Units of the Forest Service National Hierarchical Framework, smaller areas within Sections with similar surficial geology, lithology, geomorphic process, soil groups, subregional climate, and potential natural communities. FS_EcoregionSubsection is the Geodatabase domain associated with this attribute.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USDA Forest Service, Goudey and Smith (1994), Ecological Units of California-Subsections</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>FRDB Table 105a: http://www.fs.usda.gov/detail/r5/landmanagement/resourcemanagement/?cid=fsbdev3_048084</codesetn>
            <codesets>USFS Region 5</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CALVEGZONE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>General mapping areas for the CALVEG ("Classification and Assessment with Landsat of Visible Ecological Groupings") system, divided into 9 ecological zones.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USDA Forest Service, Goudey and Smith (1994), Ecological Units of California-Subsections</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>FRDB Table 36a: http://www.fs.usda.gov/detail/r5/landmanagement/resourcemanagement/?cid=fsbdev3_048008</codesetn>
            <codesets>USFS Region 5</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TILE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Tile numbers created to serve out logical portions of vegetation data for use in land management issues such as forest-wide planning efforts, wildlife habitat mapping and fire risk assessment.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USDA Forest Service, Goudey and Smith (1994), Ecological Units of California-Subsections</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Tile number</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntemail>data@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>The U.S. Forest Service makes no warranty, express or implied, nor assumes any liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness, or utility of these geospatial data or for the improper or incorrect use of those data. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible for verifying the limitations of the geospatial data and for using the data accordingly.</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20180322</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntemail>data@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>