<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Geospatial Technology and Applications Center (GTAC)</origin>
<origin>USDA Forest Service</origin>
<pubdate>20260201</pubdate>
<pubtime>175325</pubtime>
<title>RAVG Perimeters</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>The USDA Forest Service Rapid Assessment of Vegetation Condition after Wildfire (RAVG) program produces geospatial and related data representing post-fire vegetation condition by means of standardized change detection methods based on Landsat or similar multispectral satellite imagery. RAVG data products characterize the impact of disturbance (fire) on vegetation within a fire perimeter, and include estimates of percent change in live basal area (BA), percent change in canopy cover (CC), and the standardized composite burn index (CBI). Standard thematic products include 7-class percent change in basal area (BA-7), 5-class percent change in canopy cover (CC-5), and 4-class CBI (CBI-4). Contingent upon the availability of suitable imagery, RAVG products are prepared for all wildland fires reported within the conterminous United States (CONUS) that include at least 1000 acres of forested National Forest System (NFS) land (500 acres for Regions 8 and 9 as of 2016). Data for individual fires are typically made available within 45 days after fire containment ("initial assessments"). Late-season fires, however, may be deferred until the following spring or summer ("extended assessments"). Annual national mosaics of each thematic product are prepared at the end of the fire season and updated, as needed, when additional fires from the given year are processed. The annual mosaics are available via the Raster Data Warehouse (RDW, see https://apps.fs.usda.gov/arcx/rest/services/RDW_Wildfire). A combined perimeter dataset, including the burn boundaries for all published Forest Service RAVG fires from 2012 to the present, is likewise updated as needed (at least annually).</abstract>
<purpose>RAVG data are produced to assist in post-fire vegetation management planning. They are intended to enhance decision-making capabilities and reduce planning and implementation costs associated with post-fire vegetation management. The primary benefit is the cost-effective and efficient identification of potential areas of resource concern following wildfire. RAVG complements the Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) Imagery Support program, which provides information integral to determining fire effects on soils, by providing information about fire effects on existing vegetation. RAVG analysis produces a first approximation of areas that may require reforestation treatments after a fire in order to re-establish forest cover and restore associated ecosystem services. This initial approximation may be followed by site-specific diagnosis and development of a silvicultural prescription to more precisely identify reforestation needs.</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<rngdates>
<begdate>20120101</begdate>
<enddate>20220101</enddate>
</rngdates>
</timeinfo>
<current>Ground condition</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>In work</progress>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-150.529214</westbc>
<eastbc>-76.973032</eastbc>
<northbc>60.729432</northbc>
<southbc>29.213453</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>Canopy Cover</themekey>
<themekey>Burn Severity</themekey>
<themekey>CBI</themekey>
<themekey>Vegetation Condition</themekey>
<themekey>Perimeter</themekey>
<themekey>Burn Area Boundary</themekey>
<themekey>Wildfire</themekey>
<themekey>Basal Area</themekey>
<themekey>RAVG</themekey>
<themekey>Composite Burn Index</themekey>
<themekey>Wildland Fire</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
<themekey>Biota</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
<placekt>None</placekt>
<placekey>CONUS</placekey>
<placekey>United States</placekey>
</place>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>There are no restrictions on use, except for reasonable and proper acknowledgement of information sources. The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>For general EDW questions: SM.FS.data@usda.gov. For technical questions about RAVG data or processes: SM.FS.PostFireRAVG@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<datacred>USDA Forest Service, Geospatial Technology and Applications Center (GTAC)</datacred>
<secinfo>
<secsys>None</secsys>
<secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
<sechandl>None</sechandl>
</secinfo>
<native>Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.5.1.7333</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<logic>No tests for logical consistency have been performed.</logic>
<complete>This dataset is intended to include perimeters for all fires that meet standard RAVG criteria for the given years; namely, wildfires reported within CONUS that include at least 1000 acres of forested National Forest System land (at least 500 acres for Regions 8 and 9 as of 2016). Exceptions (omissions) may include fires for which suitable imagery was not available in a timely manner (i.e., within 45 days after fire containment for initial assessments).</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>The target scale of this dataset is 1:24,000. The horizontal accuracy of this dataset is determined by that of the moderate-resolution multi-spectral imagery from which it is derived.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>When a perimeter for a given fire was available from the incident management team or local unit, it was used as the initial approximation for the RAVG burned area perimeter. In many cases, supplied perimeters were edited to account for obvious discrepancies with the visible burned area (based on the post-fire imagery). If no perimeter was provided, the burned area boundary was delineated from the related satellite imagery. This step occurred on multiple dates, typically within 45 days of fire containment.</procdesc>
<procdate>20220101</procdate>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Individual fire perimeters were merged into a single vector layer. Fire perimeters comprising multiple polygons were dissolved on the fire ID.</procdesc>
<procdate>20220101</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>1158</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.RAVG_Perimeter</enttypl>
<enttypd>Feature class: A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
<enttypds>Esri GIS Data Dictionary</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Event_ID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Constructed fire identifier</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Identifier constructed from multiple fire attributes including two-letter state identifier, latitude (NNnnn), west longitude (NNNnnn), and fire ignition date (YYYYMMDD)</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Fire_Name</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Name of fire event</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Common name of fire(s) included in this data record</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>UPDATE_YMD</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Date of last update for this dataset (YYYYMMDD)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<rdom>
<rdommin>20230524</rdommin>
<rdommax>0</rdommax>
</rdom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Fire_Year</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Year of fire ignition</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<rdom>
<rdommin>2012</rdommin>
<rdommax>2022</rdommax>
<attrunit>Year</attrunit>
</rdom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PostImgYMD</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Acquisition date (YYYYMMDD) of post-fire imagery used for this assessment</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<rdom>
<rdommin>20070101</rdommin>
<rdommax>0</rdommax>
</rdom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Asmnt_Type</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Type of assessment</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>Extended</edomv>
<edomvd>Assessment based on post-fire imagery acquired near the peak of green following fire containment</edomvd>
<edomvds>USDA Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Initial</edomv>
<edomvd>Assessment based on post-fire imagery acquired within a few weeks of fire containment</edomvd>
<edomvds>USDA Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>TREE_ACRES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of pixels within this polygon identified as a tree class, in acres</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrvai>
<attrva>Value in acres</attrva>
</attrvai>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>TREE_AC_50</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of pixels within this polygon identified as tree class and with basal area loss of 50 percent or greater, in acres</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrvai>
<attrva>Value in acres</attrva>
</attrvai>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>TREE_AC_75</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of pixels within this polygon identified as tree class and with basal area loss of 75 percent or greater, in acres</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrvai>
<attrva>Value in acres</attrva>
</attrvai>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>EVT_VER</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Version of LANDFIRE Existing Vegetation Type (EVT) used for this data record</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>LF2001_EVT105</edomv>
<edomvd>EVT version 1.0.5 (LF2001)</edomvd>
<edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>LF2014_EVT140</edomv>
<edomvd>EVT version 1.4.0 (LF2014)</edomvd>
<edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>LF2020_EVT220</edomv>
<edomvd>EVT version 2.2.0 (LF2020)</edomvd>
<edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>LF2016_EVT200</edomv>
<edomvd>EVT version 2.0.0 (LF2016)</edomvd>
<edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>LF2012_EVT130</edomv>
<edomvd>EVT version 1.3.0 (LF2012)</edomvd>
<edomvds>LANDFIRE</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PreImgYMD</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Acquisition date (YYYYMMDD) of pre-fire imagery used for this assessment</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<rdom>
<rdommin>20040101</rdommin>
<rdommax>0</rdommax>
</rdom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Acres</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area enclosed by perimeter, in acres</attrdef>
<attrdefs>USDA Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<rdom>
<rdommin>500</rdommin>
<rdommax>0</rdommax>
</rdom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20240508</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
