<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<title>Emergency Situation Determination Lands</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<onlink>https://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/datasets.php?xmlKeyword=emergency+situation</onlink>
<onlink>https://usfs.maps.arcgis.com/home/item.html?id=817a9d13df5f4f3d8c22bd09fe2627b9</onlink>
<onlink>https://www.fs.usda.gov/rds/archive/catalog/RDS-2015-0047-4</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>Emergency Situation Determination (ESD) lands, per the Secretary's Memo 1078-006: Increasing Timber Production and Designating an Emergency Situation on National Forest System Lands, have been designated by either being at risk from insect and diseases under the Healthy Forest Restoration Act, or have a high or very high wildfire hazard potential. Only Forest Service owned lands are included in this feature. https://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/edw_resources/meta/BdyDesg_HFRA_EmergencySituationDetermination.xml</abstract>
<purpose>This data represents areas designated as Emergency Situation Determination lands owned by the National Forests by the USDA Secretary's Memo 1078-006 Emergency Situation Determination (ESD) that, under section 40807 of the Infrastructure and Jobs Act (IIJA), identified all National Forest System lands that are eligible for insect and disease treatments under section 602 and 603 of the Healthy Forest Restoration Act and all National Forest System lands designated as having a high or very high wildfire hazard potential.  </purpose>
<supplinf>Two components of ESD are HFRA and WHP.   
HEALTHY FOREST RESTORATION ACT (HFRA - see metadata url link) -- The feature includes National Forest System (NFS) Lands within 37 States designated under section 602 and 603 of the Healthy Forest Restoration Act as of 2022 determinations. Designated areas were selected based on a set of eligibility criteria regarding forest health and should not include any areas coinciding with Wilderness and Wilderness Study Areas. The data is comprised of selected HUC-6 units or other areas of similar size and scope clipped to Proclaimed National Forest System lands. Non-Forest Service land ownership areas (inholdings) are also removed. In some cases, entire National Forests were designated.     
WILDFIRE HAZARD POTENTIAL (WHP - see metadata url link) -- The feature includes areas classified as high or very high from the 2023 version of Wildfire Hazard Potential mapping for the United States within National Forest System lands, non-Forest Service land ownership removed. No high or very high areas were located within Region 10 forests for the Alaska WHP dataset. WHP is an index that quantifies the relative potential for high-intensity wildfire that may be difficult to manage, used as a measure to help prioritize where fuel treatments may be needed. This 2023 version of WHP was created from updated national wildfire hazard datasets of annual burn probability and fire intensity generated by the USDA Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station with the large fire simulation system (FSim). Vegetation and wildland fuels data from LANDFIRE 2020 (version 2.2.0) were the primary inputs to the updated FSim modeling work and therefore form the foundation for this version of the WHP. As such, the data presented here reflect landscape conditions as of the end of 2020. LANDFIRE 2020 vegetation and fuels data were also used directly in the WHP mapping process, along with updated point locations of fire occurrence ca. 1992-2020. With these datasets as inputs, an index of WHP for all of the conterminous United States at 270-meter resolution was produced. A final WHP mapping was made with five WHP classes of very low, low, moderate, high, and very high. On its own, WHP is not an explicit map of wildfire threat or risk, but when paired with spatial data depicting highly valued resources and assets such as structures or powerlines, it can approximate relative wildfire risk to those specific resources and assets. WHP is also not a forecast or wildfire outlook for any particular season, as it does not include any information on current or forecasted weather or fuel moisture conditions. It is instead intended for long-term strategic fuels management.</supplinf>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20250404</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>Unknown</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>None planned</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-149.99999146</westbc>
<eastbc>-71.002870776</eastbc>
<northbc>60.68642568</northbc>
<southbc>28.627328781</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
<themekey>environment; health; geoscientific​Information; society</themekey>
</theme>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
<country>US</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<datacred>USDA Forest Service, US Forest Service Geospatial Office, US Forest Service Enterprise Map Services Program, USDA Forest Service, Fire Modeling Institute, which is part of the Rocky Mountain Research Station, Fire, Fuel and Smoke Science Program, USDA Forest Service, Fire and Aviation Management, USDA Forest Service, Fire Modeling Institute.</datacred>
<native>
</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<logic>National</logic>
<complete>Please note that this data represents data presented as part of Secretary's Memo 1078-006: Increasing Timber Production and Designating an Emergency Situation on National Forest System Lands. The data used in that presentation included the HFRA determinations up through 2022 as they existed in the enterprise data systems. HFRA areas added in 2023 in Oregon were not included in the mapping.  WHP raster data may be mapped in areas that may not be available for timber management, such as Wilderness, Wild and Scenic Rivers, Inventoried Roadless Areas and other reserved designations.   The raster dataset is based on 270 meter pixels and as such should not be used with fine scale (project level) activities.</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>HFRA data is based on large areas with relatively low accuracy, clipped with National Forest boundaries with high accuracy.   WHP data is based on 270 meter pixels and as such should not be used with fine scale (project level) activities.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>The input data is EDW data - a vector map (Healthy Forests Restoration Act - Insects and Diseases, 2022 version) and the Wildfire Hazard Potential raster (2023 version). Polygonization of the WHP involved no simplification of geographies. No Forest Service land management units were erased/removed from WHP dataset. </procdesc>
<procdate>20250327</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>Complete chain</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>144656</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.BdyDesg_EmergencySituationDetermination</enttypl>
<enttypd>Feature class: A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
<enttypds>ESRI GIS Dictionary</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ESD</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Emergency Situation Determination (ESD) as presented in mapping associated with Secretary Memo 1078-006: Increasing Timber Production and Designating an Emergency Situation on National Forest System Lands, 4 April 2025.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Part of ESD: Y - Yes, N - No</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Esri field of boundary area in coordinate system units</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Esri field of boundary length in coordinate system units</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Esri field of boundary length in coordinate system units</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Esri field of boundary length in coordinate system units </udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20250425</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
<country>US</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
