<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>U.S. Forest Service</origin>
<origin>Rebecca Lilja, U.S. Forest Service, GIS Specialist</origin>
<pubdate>20140930</pubdate>
<title>S_USA.FORESTSONTHEEDGE</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<onlink>http://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/datasets.php</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>These data have been depreciated and an updated dataset is available titled Forests to Faucets 2.0 (2022).  More information about Forests to Faucets 2.0 can be found at: https://www.fs.usda.gov/ecosystemservices/FS_Efforts/forests2faucets.shtml

The Forests on the Edge feature class is based on the digital hydrologic unit boundary layer to the Subwatershed (12-digit) 6th level for the continental United States. This 2015 data set is an updated version of the 2011 Forests to Faucets data set. America’s private forests provide a vast array of public goods and services, including abundant, clean surface water. Forest loss and development can affect water quality and quantity when forests are removed and impervious surfaces, such as paved roads, spread across the landscape. In this study rank watersheds across the conterminous United States were ranked according to the contributions of private forest land to surface drinking water and by threats to surface water from increased housing density. Private forest land contributions to drinking water are greatest in the East but are also important in Western watersheds. Development pressures on these contributions are concentrated in the Eastern United States but are also found in the North-Central region, parts of the West and Southwest, and the Pacific Northwest; nationwide, more than 55 million acres of rural private forest land are projected to experience a substantial increase in housing density from 2000 to 2030. Planners, communities, and private landowners can use a range of strategies to maintain freshwater ecosystems, including designing housing and roads to minimize impacts on water quality, managing home sites to protect water resources, and using payment schemes and management partnerships to invest in forest stewardship on public and private lands.</abstract>
<purpose>These data have been depreciated and an updated dataset is available titled Forests to Faucets 2.0 (2022).  More information about Forests to Faucets 2.0 can be found at: https://www.fs.usda.gov/ecosystemservices/FS_Efforts/forests2faucets.shtml

The purpose of these data is to support the publication RMRS-GTR-327, Private forests, housing growth, and America’s water supply: A report from the Forests on the Edge and Forests to Faucets Projects. This dataset updates forest and development statistics reported in the 2011 Forests to Faucet analysis.</purpose>
</descript>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>None planned</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-124.859937</westbc>
<eastbc>-66.183029</eastbc>
<northbc>49.384479</northbc>
<southbc>24.512236</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>community</themekey>
<themekey>stewardship</themekey>
<themekey>forest</themekey>
<themekey>Forests on the Edge</themekey>
<themekey>development</themekey>
<themekey>USFS</themekey>
<themekey>Forests to Faucets</themekey>
<themekey>drinking water</themekey>
</theme>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>U.S. Forest Service</cntorg>
<cntper>Rebecca Lilja</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
<address>271 Mast Rd</address>
<city>Durham</city>
<state>NH</state>
<postal>03824</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>603-868-7627</cntvoice>
<cntemail>rlilja@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
<hours>8:00 - 5:00 ET</hours>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<datacred>Mockrin, M.H.; Lilja, R.L.; Weidner, E.; Stein, S.M.; Carr, M.A. 2014. Private forests, housing growth, and America’s water supply: A report from the Forests on the Edge and Forests to Faucets Projects. Gen. Tech. Rep. RMRS-GTR-327. Fort Collins, CO: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station. 29 p. http://www.fs.fed.us/openspace/fote/private-forests.html</datacred>
<native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.7.1.11595</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<logic>Data entry is accomplished by authorized Forest Service personnel through a web application behind the U.S. Forest Service firewall and is restricted by access requirement protocols.</logic>
<complete>Data is complete as of publication.</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>Generally the source information used to record spatial locations are from: 1) on-screen digitizing with a georeferenced topographic or image background; or 2) GPS field collected positions. Horizontal accuracy is variable.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>To focus this analysis on watersheds with private forests, only watersheds with at least 10% forested land and more than 50 acres of private forest were analyzed. All other watersheds were labeled "Insufficient private forest for this analysis" and coded -99999 in the data table. This dataset updates forest and development statistics reported in the 2011 Forests to Faucet analysis using 2006 National Land Cover Database for the Conterminous United States, and Theobald, Dr. David M. 10 March 2008. bhc2000 and bhc2030 (Housing density for the coterminous US in 2000 and 2030, respectively.)</procdesc>
<procdate>20140101</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>82923</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.FORESTSONTHEEDGE</enttypl>
<enttypd>Feature Class: A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
<enttypds>http://support.esri.com/en/knowledgebase/GISDictionary/term/feature%20class</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STATES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>States that the HUC12 crosses</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Federal Guidelines, Requirements, and Procedures for the National Watershed Boundary Dataset; Chapter 3 of Section A, Federal Standards, Book 11, Collection and Delineation of Spatial Data; Techniques and Methods 11-A3. </attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>State abbreviation(s) as text.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>HUC_12</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Twelve Digit Hydrologic Unit Code: This field provides a unique 12-digit code for each subwatershed. Numbers were assigned in an upstream to downstream fashion. Where no downstream/upstream relationship could be determined numbers were assigned in a clockwise fashion. </attrdef>
<attrdefs>Federal Guidelines, Requirements, and Procedures for the National Watershed Boundary Dataset; Chapter 3 of Section A, Federal Standards, Book 11, Collection and Delineation of Spatial Data; Techniques and Methods 11-A3. </attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Twelve Digit Code</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>HU_12_NAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Twelve Digit Hydrologic Unit Code Name</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Federal Guidelines, Requirements, and Procedures for the National Watershed Boundary Dataset; Chapter 3 of Section A, Federal Standards, Book 11, Collection and Delineation of Spatial Data; Techniques and Methods 11-A3. </attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>HUC Name</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>HU_12_DS</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Sixth Level Downstream Hydrologic Unit Code: This field was populated with the 12-digit code of the 6th level hydrologic unit that is receiving the majority of the flow from the subwatershed.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Federal Guidelines, Requirements, and Procedures for the National Watershed Boundary Dataset; Chapter 3 of Section A, Federal Standards, Book 11, Collection and Delineation of Spatial Data; Techniques and Methods 11-A3. </attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Twelve Digit Code</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>IMP1</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Index of surface drinking water importance. This field is from the 2011 Forests to Faucet analysis and has not been updated for this analysis. It was the index numbers ranked and normalized to be on a 1-100 scale</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Weidner, E.; Todd, A. 2011. From the forest to the faucet: drinking water and forests in the US. Methods paper. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service. 34 p.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Integer between 1 and 100.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>HDCHG_AC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Acres of housing density change on private forest in the subwatershed. This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs> Fry, J., Xian, G., Jin, S., Dewitz, J., Homer, C., Yang, L., Barnes, C., Herold, N., and Wickham, J., 2011. 2006 National Land Cover Database for the Conterminous United States, PE&amp;RS, Vol. 77(9):858-864. and Theobald, Dr. David M. 10 March 2008. bhc2000 and bhc2030 (Housing density for the coterminous US in 2000 and 2030, respectively.) Colorado State University, Ft. Collins, CO. </attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Acres</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>HDCHG_PER</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Percent of the watershed to experience housing density change on private forest. This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs> Fry, J., Xian, G., Jin, S., Dewitz, J., Homer, C., Yang, L., Barnes, C., Herold, N., and Wickham, J., 2011. 2006 National Land Cover Database for the Conterminous United States, PE&amp;RS, Vol. 77(9):858-864. and Theobald, Dr. David M. 10 March 2008. bhc2000 and bhc2030 (Housing density for the coterminous US in 2000 and 2030, respectively.) Colorado State University, Ft. Collins, CO. </attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Percent</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>IMP_HD_PFOR</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Index Private Forest importance to Surface Drinking Water with Development Pressure - identifies private forested areas important for surface drinking water that are likely to be affected by future increases in housing density. This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Mockrin, M.H.; Lilja, R.L.; Weidner, E.; Stein, S.M.; Carr, M.A. 2014. Private forests, housing growth, and America’s water supply: A report from the Forests on the Edge and Forests to Faucets Projects. Gen. Tech. Rep. RMRS-GTR-327. Fort Collins, CO: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station. 29 p.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Index value calculation: ([IMP1] * [PFOR_PER] * [HDCHG_PER])/10000</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PTLE_IMP_HD</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Private Forest importance to Surface Drinking Water with Development Pressure (Figure 7). This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Mockrin, M.H.; Lilja, R.L.; Weidner, E.; Stein, S.M.; Carr, M.A. 2014. Private forests, housing growth, and America’s water supply: A report from the Forests on the Edge and Forests to Faucets Projects. Gen. Tech. Rep. RMRS-GTR-327. Fort Collins, CO: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station. 29 p.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Percentile</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PTLE_HDCHG</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Percentile of each subwatershed to Experience an increase in House Density in Private Forest (Figure 6). This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Mockrin, M.H.; Lilja, R.L.; Weidner, E.; Stein, S.M.; Carr, M.A. 2014. Private forests, housing growth, and America’s water supply: A report from the Forests on the Edge and Forests to Faucets Projects. Gen. Tech. Rep. RMRS-GTR-327. Fort Collins, CO: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station. 29 p.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Percentile</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FOR_AC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Acres forest in the subwatershed derived from the 2006 National Land Cover Database for the Conterminous United States. This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data. This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Fry, J., Xian, G., Jin, S., Dewitz, J., Homer, C., Yang, L., Barnes, C., Herold, N., and Wickham, J., 2011. 2006 National Land Cover Database for the Conterminous United States, PE&amp;RS, Vol. 77(9):858-864.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Acres</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PFOR_AC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Acres private forest in the subwatershed. This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>(1)The Conservation Biology Institute (CBI.) October 21, 2012. PAD‐US (CBI Edition) Version 2. Corvallis, Oregon. (2) Fry, J., Xian, G., Jin, S., Dewitz, J., Homer, C., Yang, L., Barnes, C., Herold, N., and Wickham, J., 2011. 2006 National Land Cover Database for the Conterminous United States, PE&amp;RS, Vol. 77(9):858-864.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Acres</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PFOR_PER</attrlabl>
<attrdef>(PFOR_AC / HU12_AC) * 100 Percent of the subwatershed that is private forest. This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>(1)The Conservation Biology Institute (CBI.) October 21, 2012. PAD‐US (CBI Edition) Version 2. Corvallis, Oregon. (2) Fry, J., Xian, G., Jin, S., Dewitz, J., Homer, C., Yang, L., Barnes, C., Herold, N., and Wickham, J., 2011. 2006 National Land Cover Database for the Conterminous United States, PE&amp;RS, Vol. 77(9):858-864.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Percent</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>HU12_AC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Acreage of the subwatershed</attrdef>
<attrdefs>GIS Calculated</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Acres</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FOR_PER</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Percent of the subwatershed that is forest. Derived from the 2006 National Land Cover Database for the Conterminous United States. Photogrammetric-Engineering-and-Remote-Sensing. 77:858-864. This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>GIS Calculated</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Percent. Calculation: (FOR_AC/ HU12_AC) * 100</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PFOR_IMP</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Index of Private Forest Importance to Surface Drinking Water. This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Weidner, E.; Todd, A. 2011. From the forest to the faucet: drinking water and forests in the US. Methods paper. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service. 34 p.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Index value. Calculation: ([IMP1] * [PFOR_PER])/100</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PTLE_PFIMP</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Private forest importance to surface drinking water(Figure 4). This field is an update to the original Forests to Faucet data.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Mockrin, M.H.; Lilja, R.L.; Weidner, E.; Stein, S.M.; Carr, M.A. 2014. Private forests, housing growth, and America’s water supply: A report from the Forests on the Edge and Forests to Faucets Projects. Gen. Tech. Rep. RMRS-GTR-327. Fort Collins, CO: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station. 29 p.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Percentile</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>TOP100</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Top 100 subwatersheds. 50 from the East, 50 from the West (using the Mississippi River as the divide.) (Figure 8)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Mockrin, M.H.; Lilja, R.L.; Weidner, E.; Stein, S.M.; Carr, M.A. 2014. Private forests, housing growth, and America’s water supply: A report from the Forests on the Edge and Forests to Faucets Projects. Gen. Tech. Rep. RMRS-GTR-327. Fort Collins, CO: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station. 29 p.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Number rank (from 1 to 50) and E for East or W for West.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>TOP50EW</attrlabl>
<attrdef>This field indicates whether the subwatershed is within the top 50 in the East or the West.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Mockrin, M.H.; Lilja, R.L.; Weidner, E.; Stein, S.M.; Carr, M.A. 2014. Private forests, housing growth, and America’s water supply: A report from the Forests on the Edge and Forests to Faucets Projects. Gen. Tech. Rep. RMRS-GTR-327. Fort Collins, CO: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Rocky Mountain Research Station. 29 p.</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>1</edomv>
<edomvd>Subwatershed is within the top 50 in the East</edomvd>
<edomvds>USFS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>2</edomv>
<edomvd>Subwatershed is within the top 50 in the West</edomvd>
<edomvds>USFS</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Area of feature in internal units squared.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Length of feature in internal units.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20230623</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USFS Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>data@fs.fed.us</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
