<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>U.S. Forest Service</origin>
<pubdate>20220531</pubdate>
<pubtime>143634</pubtime>
<title>S_USA.RoadlessArea_CO_2012</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<onlink>http://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/datasets.php</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>This feature class describes the boundaries of Roadless Areas designated by the Colorado Roadless Rule of 2012 and managed by the U.S. Forest Service. These roadless areas were designated by administrative rulemaking to provide management direction for conservation of roadless area characteristics while addressing Colorado specific concerns. These roadless area designations supersede the roadless areas designated by the Roadless Area Conservation Rule of 2001 for Colorado. Upper tier areas are a subset of Colorado Roadless Areas which have limited exceptions to provide a high level of protection. The North Fork Coal Mining area is a subset of Colorado Roadless Areas which has an exception for coal mining related activities.</abstract>
<purpose>This feature class describes the boundaries of Roadless Areas designated by the Colorado Roadless Rule of 2012 and managed by the U.S. Forest Service. These roadless areas were designated by administrative rulemaking to provide management direction for conservation of roadless area characteristics while addressing Colorado specific concerns. These roadless area designations supersede the roadless areas designated by the Roadless Area Conservation Rule of 2001 for Colorado.</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>20150218</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>publication date</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>As needed</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-109.060258</westbc>
<eastbc>-104.867423</eastbc>
<northbc>41.003433</northbc>
<southbc>37.027880</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>Inventoried Roadless Areas</themekey>
<themekey>Colorado Roadless Rule</themekey>
<themekey>Roadless Area</themekey>
</theme>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>U.S. Forest Service Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<datacred>U.S. Forest Service</datacred>
<native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.7.1.11595</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<logic>None</logic>
<complete>None</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>Generally the source information used to record spatial locations are from: 1) on-screen digitizing with a georeferenced topographic or image background; or 2) GPS field collected positions.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Areas qualifying as "roadless" are delineated and attributed by forests and regions. The data has been revised from the 2001 Roadless areas to incorporate more acreage and special cases within Colorado. Changes to the Colorado Roadless Rule are subject to public review and comment, subject to 36 CFR 294 Subpart D. The spatial processing history dates back to the Inventoried Roadless Rule of 2001. More information can be found at http://www.fs.usda.gov/roadmain/roadless/coloradoroadlessrules</procdesc>
<procdate>20120501</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>532</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.RoadlessArea_CO_2012</enttypl>
<enttypd>A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
<enttypds>http://support.esri.com/en/knowledgebase/GISDictionary/term/feature%20class</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ROADLESSAREANAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The official name of the roadless area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Roadless area names are unique to each area.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MGMTCLASSIFICATIONCODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The code describing the management classification of the roadless area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>BCR</edomv>
<edomvd>Backcountry Restoration</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>GFRG</edomv>
<edomvd>General Forest, Rangeland, and Grassland</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>P</edomv>
<edomvd>Primitive</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>SAHTS</edomv>
<edomvd>Special Area of Historic or Tribal Significance</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>FPSA</edomv>
<edomvd>Forest Plan Special Area</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>WLR</edomv>
<edomvd>Wild Land Recreation</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>MGMTCLASSIFICATION</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The management classification type of the roadless area.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<edom>
<edomv>General Roadless</edomv>
<edomvd>Areas designated pursuant to 36 CFR 294 Subpart D and identified in a set of maps maintained at the national headquarters office of the Forest Service.  Colorado Roadless Areas established by this subpart shall constitute the exclusive set of the National Forest System lands within the State of Colorado to which the provisions 36 CFR 220.5 (a) (2) shall apply.</edomvd>
<edomvds>U.S. Forest Service</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>Upper Tier</edomv>
<edomvd>Upper tier acres are a subset of CRAs that have limited exceptions to provide a high-level of protection for these areas. Alternative 2 in the RDEIS designated 562,200 acres as upper tier. This quantity of upper tier acres was based on roadless areas with existing forest plan direction that prohibits road construction and reconstruction for all national forests, except for the GMUG and San Juan National Forests. For the GMUG and San Juan National Forests, upper tier acres were defined by examining proposed forest plan direction and selecting lands where road construction and reconstruction within roadless areas was prohibited. This approach was used to build on the previous collaborative public input processes, which helped to develop the existing and revised forest plans. Generally, the forest planning process determined that roadless areas with forest plan direction prohibiting road construction and reconstruction are high value roadless areas, and this is the basis for the upper tier.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Taken from:  Rulemaking for Colorado Roadless Areas, Volume II, Final Environmental Impact Statement May 2012, Chapter 2 Alternatives, Including the Proposed Action, pg. 24.</edomvds>
</edom>
<edom>
<edomv>North Fork Coal Mining Area</edomv>
<edomvd>This alternative designates 19,100 acres of CRAs on the GMUG National Forests as the North Fork coal mining area. Temporary road construction and reconstruction for activities associated with coal mining would be allowed on these lands (Map 13 in map packet). Such roads also may be used for collecting and transporting methane gas from coal mines. Buried infrastructure, including pipelines, needed for the capture, collection, and use of coal mine methane would be located within the rights-of-way of temporary roads that are otherwise necessary for coal-related surface activities, including the installation and operation of methane venting wells. No upper tier acres are designated in the North Fork coal mining area under this alternative.</edomvd>
<edomvds>Taken from:  Rulemaking for Colorado Roadless Areas, Volume II, Final Environmental Impact Statement May 2012, Chapter 2 Alternatives, Including the Proposed Action, pg. 29.</edomvds>
</edom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>REGIONCODE_CA2012</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The code for the  U.S. Forest Service Region in which this roadless area exists, at the time of the roadless rule (2012)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Two digit Region Code.  For example "01" for Northern Region.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>REGIONNAME_CA2012</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the U.S. Forest Service Region in which this roadless area exists at the time of the roadless rule (2012)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The Region Name.  For example, Northern or Intermountain</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FORESTCODE_CA2012</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The code of the National Forest in which this roadless area exists, at the time of the roadless rule (2012).</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The two digit forest code.  For example 13 for Salmon-Challis National Forest</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FORESTNAME_CA2012</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the National Forest in which this roadless area exists, at the time of the roadless rule (2012).</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The forest name.  For example:  Salmon-Challis National Forest</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FORESTORGCODE_CA2012</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The concatenation of the region and forest code of the National Forest in which the roadless area exists, at the time of the roadless rule (2012)</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The four digit organization code for the National Forest in the format RRFF where RR is the region code and FF is the forest code.  For example, 0413 for the Salmon-Challis National Forest in the Intermountain Region</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STATECODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The two character state abbreviation for the state in which the roadless area occurs</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Census</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The two digit state abbreviation of the state in which the roadless area is located.  For example AL for Alabama</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STATENAME</attrlabl>
<attrdef>The name of the state in which the roadless area occurs.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>US Census</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The name of the state in which the roadless area occurs.  For example, Alabama</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACRES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Acres of the roadless area as calculated by the GIS in NAD83 UTM 13N.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Area measured in acres.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20230623</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>U.S. Forest Service Chief Information Office, Enterprise Data Warehouse</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>physical</addrtype>
<city>Washington</city>
<state>DC</state>
<postal>20250</postal>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>Please send an e-mail to the address below.</cntvoice>
<cntemail>SM.FS.data@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
