<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>U.S. Forest Service</origin>
<pubdate>20250411</pubdate>
<pubtime>164156</pubtime>
<title>S_USA.BdyPlan_HealthyForestRestoration_2023</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<onlink>http://data.fs.usda.gov/geodata/edw/datasets.php</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>The Healthy Forest Restoration Act feature class depicts National Forest System (NFS) Lands within 37 States designated under section 602 and 603 of the Healthy Forest Restoration Act. Designated areas were selected based on a set of eligibility criteria regarding forest health and do not include any areas coinciding with Wilderness and Wilderness Study Areas. The data is comprised of selected HUC-6 units or other areas of similar size and scope clipped to Proclaimed National Forest System lands. Non-Forest Service land ownership areas (inholdings) are also removed. In some cases, entire National Forests were designated. Some state designations' methodologies may differ from the national standard. Please note that HealthyForestRestoration_2023 is an archived version. The most current version of this data is contained in the feature class named simply HealthyForestRestoration. Therefore, the most current layer along with previous years' data are available, and the user should ensure that they understand which layer is being accessed. Previous years' data will have a date stamp in the file name, while the most current layer will not. Further, the attribute, "Latest_Revision_Date" contains the date of the most recent designation layer for each state.</abstract>
<purpose>This data represents areas designated within National Forest System Lands, in 37 States, that are eligible for insect and disease treatments under section 602 and 603 of the Healthy Forest Restoration Act. This is a previous version of the dataset, archived in 2023.</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<rngdates>
<begdate>20140520</begdate>
<enddate>20240101</enddate>
</rngdates>
</timeinfo>
<current>publication date</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>Annually</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>-149.999991</westbc>
<eastbc>-71.002231</eastbc>
<northbc>60.686866</northbc>
<southbc>28.978100</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
</theme>
<theme>
<themekt>None</themekt>
<themekey>Designations</themekey>
<themekey>National Forest System Lands</themekey>
<themekey>Healthy Forest Restoration Act</themekey>
<themekey>Section 602 and 603</themekey>
<themekey>Insect and Disease</themekey>
<themekey>Farm Bill</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
<placekt>None</placekt>
<placekey>West Virginia</placekey>
<placekey>Oklahoma</placekey>
<placekey>New York</placekey>
<placekey>Ohio</placekey>
<placekey>Florida</placekey>
<placekey>Alaska</placekey>
<placekey>Washington</placekey>
<placekey>New Hampshire</placekey>
<placekey>Michigan</placekey>
<placekey>Virginia</placekey>
<placekey>Tennessee</placekey>
<placekey>Colorado</placekey>
<placekey>Vermont</placekey>
<placekey>Montana</placekey>
<placekey>Missouri</placekey>
<placekey>Alabama</placekey>
<placekey>Idaho</placekey>
<placekey>Louisiana</placekey>
<placekey>California</placekey>
<placekey>Minnesota</placekey>
<placekey>Texas</placekey>
<placekey>Mississippi</placekey>
<placekey>South Carolina</placekey>
<placekey>Kentucky</placekey>
<placekey>Georgia</placekey>
<placekey>South Dakota</placekey>
<placekey>New Mexico</placekey>
<placekey>Nevada</placekey>
<placekey>Arkansas</placekey>
<placekey>Arizona</placekey>
<placekey>Wyoming.</placekey>
<placekey>Utah</placekey>
<placekey>Oregon</placekey>
<placekey>Pennsylvania</placekey>
<placekey>North Carolina</placekey>
<placekey>Indiana</placekey>
<placekey>Wisconsin</placekey>
</place>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The USDA Forest Service makes no warranty, expressed or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose, nor assumes any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, reliability, completeness or utility of these geospatial data, or for the improper or incorrect use of these geospatial data. These geospatial data and related maps or graphics are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The data and maps may not be used to determine title, ownership, legal descriptions or boundaries, legal jurisdiction, or restrictions that may be in place on either public or private land. Natural hazards may or may not be depicted on the data and maps, and land users should exercise due caution. The data are dynamic and may change over time. The user is responsible to verify the limitations of the geospatial data and to use the data accordingly.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USDA Forest Service</cntorg>
<cntper>Trevor Long</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntpos>Technology Integration Unit Leadert</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
<address>125 South State Street, Suite 7105</address>
<city>Salt Lake City</city>
<state>UT</state>
<postal>84138</postal>
<country>US</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>801-975-3838</cntvoice>
<cntemail>trevor.long@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.9.1.28388</native>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<logic>Spatial data was visually inspected to ensure that no invalid gaps or polygon overlaps exist within the dataset. Topological tests using Esri ArcGIS were also done to ensure the same. Attribute data was also visually inspected for completeness.</logic>
<complete>Please note that this data is current as of the last collection date, and changes to designated areas will be republished and archived on weekly basis. Therefore, the most current layer along with previous years' data are available, and the user should ensure that they understand which layer is being accessed. Previous years' data will have a date stamp in the file name, while the most current layer will not. Further, the attribute, "Latest_Revision_Date" contains the date of the most recent designation layer for each state.</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>Generally the source information used to record spatial locations are from: 1) on-screen digitizing with a georeferenced topographic or image background; or 2) GPS field collected positions.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Spatial data is extracted from a file geodatabase containing areas for Healthy Forestation Act Designations. The area of each polygon is calculated in acres during the load into the EDW. The data is loaded into the EDW in the HealthyForestRestorationAct feature dataset and the publication date in the metadata is update to reflect the date of the data refresh. The refresh is done on an as-needed basis.</procdesc>
<procdate>20231231</procdate>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>38</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>S_USA.HealthyForestRestoration</enttypl>
<enttypd>A collection of geographic features with the same geometry type (such as point, line, or polygon), the same attributes, and the same spatial reference.</enttypd>
<enttypds>http://support.esri.com/en/knowledgebase/GISDictionary/term/feature%20class</enttypds>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>LATEST_REVISION_DATE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>This is the date of the most recent revision to a state's designation layer.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Date.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACRES_WITH_INHOLDINGS_REMOVED</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Acres of designated areas within National Forest System Lands with non-FS inholdings removed</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Numerical acreage values (not prescribed)</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>STATE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>State Name</attrdef>
<attrdefs>U.S. Forest Service</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Names of States in the United States of America</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>GIS_ACRES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of a feature in acres, calculated by converting Decimal Degrees to meters with the formula AreaMeters * 0.0002471054.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>Geometry</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>The area of a feature in acres.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20250501</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>USDA Forest Service</cntorg>
<cntper>Trevor Long</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntpos>Technology Integration Unit Leadert</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
<address>125 South State Street, Suite 7105</address>
<city>Salt Lake City</city>
<state>UT</state>
<postal>84138</postal>
<country>US</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>801-975-3838</cntvoice>
<cntemail>trevor.long@usda.gov</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
